橄榄球赛开赛前 场上总是很安静
There's a moment of orderly silence before a football play begins.
球员全部就位 前锋纹丝不动 谁也不知道将会发生什么
Players are in position, linemen are frozen, and anything is possible.
（在这十月中旬的天气几乎和印第安的夏天一样）
(Almost Indian-summer weather here in mid-November.)
之后就像一场车祸 球员开始互相乱撞
Then, like a traffic accident, stuff begins to randomly collide.
从开球到第一次碰撞...
From the snap of the ball to the snap of the first bone...
也就四五秒时间
is closer to four seconds than five.
（首攻10码 瑞金斯快速跳到了赛斯曼的背后）
(First and 10. Riggins  flea flicker back to Theismann.)
（赛斯曼有了大麻烦）
(Theismann's in a lot of trouble.)
第一秒 红人队的四分卫乔•赛斯曼...
One Mississippi. Joe Theismann, the Redskins' quarterback...
抢到球并传给他的跑锋
takes the snap and hands off to his running back.
（首攻10码 瑞金斯...）
(First and 10. Riggins...)
第二秒
Two Mississippi.
这是一种叫 "flea flicker" 的战术
It's a trick play, a flea flicker...
跑锋又把球传回给四分卫
and the running back tosses the ball back to the quarterback.
（快速跳到了赛斯曼的背后）
(Flea flicker back to Theismann.)
第三秒
Three Mississippi.
直到现在 四分卫似乎掌握了场上的主动权
Up to now, the play's been defined by what the quarterback sees.
但危险正从他背后靠近
It's about to be defined by what he doesn't.
第四秒
Four Mississippi.
劳伦斯•泰勒 从踏入球场的那天起...
Lawrence Taylor is the best defensive player in the NFL...
就注定是全美橄榄球联盟史上最优秀的防守
and has been from the time he stepped onto the field as a rookie.
（赛斯曼有了大麻烦）
(Theismann's in a lot of trouble.)
（是劳伦斯•泰勒...）
(And it was Lawrence Taylor...)
（在42码线的位置他把赛斯曼按倒在地上）
(who slammed Theismann to the ground at the 42-yard line.)
（动作快如闪电...）
(The blitz was on...)
而他也将改变我们所熟悉的橄榄球比赛
He will also change the game of football as we know it.
（让我们从反角度再看一次）
(And we'll look at it with the reverse angle one more time.)
（请注意 场面比较惨烈）
(And I suggest if your stomach is weak, you just don't watch.)
传奇式的四分卫 乔•塞斯曼
Legendary quarterback Joe Theismann...
从此离开了球场
never played another down of football.
现在你们应该能猜到
Now, y'all would guess that, more often than not...
联盟中薪水最高的通常是四分卫...
the highest paid player on an NFL team is a quarterback...
的确如此
and you'd be right.
而你们不知道的是
But what you probably don't know is, more often than not...
多亏了劳伦斯•泰勒 薪水第二高的通常是左前锋
the second highest paid player is, thanks to Lawrence Taylor, a left tackle.
这就像多数家庭主妇那样 第一张支票还房贷...
Because as every housewife knows, the first check you write is for the mortgage...
第二张就要买保险
but the second is for the insurance.
左前锋的任务就是保护四分卫
And the left tackle's job is to protect the quarterback from what he can't see coming.
防止对方从他的盲点向他进攻
To protect his blind side.
理想的左前锋应该是个大块头 但这种人很多
The ideal left tackle is big, but a lot of people are big.
他必须骨盆宽大 大腿粗壮
He's wide in the butt and massive in the thighs.
手臂长 手掌大 跑得还要快
He has long arms, giant hands and feet as quick as a hiccup.
满足全部条件的人少之又少...
This is a rare and expensive combination...
这种人很抢手 不仅因为那个周一晚上的球赛...
the need for which can be traced to that Monday night game...
也因为劳伦斯•泰勒
and Lawrence Taylor.
因为在那一天 他不仅改变了乔•塞斯曼的生活...
For on that day, he not only altered Joe Theismann's life...
也改变了我的生活
but mine as well.
欧尔先生
Mr. Oher.
你明不明白？知道我为什么找你吗？
Do you understand? Do you know why I'm here?
想...调查？
To investigate?
对 调查
Yes. To investigate.
我想调查你不寻常的...处境
I'm here to investigate your odd...predicament.
你觉得你的处境奇怪吗？
Do you find it odd, your predicament?
麦克？
Michael?
不知道
I don't know.
- 我...可以走了吗？- 不行
- Can I...? Can I leave now? - No, you can't.
（两年前）
片名：弱点
克顿教练的办公室在哪？
Where's Coach Cotton's office?
谢谢
Thanks  man.
据说你是教练
They said you were the coach.
伯特•克顿
Bert Cotton.
东尼•汉弥尔顿 不过大家都叫我大托
Tony Hamilton, but everybody just calls me Big Tony.
嘿 大麦 看
Hey, Big Mike, check it out.
没上锁
Not even locked.
白人脑子都进水了
White people are crazy.
孩子他妈临死前...
promised my ma, Boo, on her deathbed...
我答应让他的儿子史提芬离开公立学校 去上教会学校
that I'd get my son, Steven, out of public school and into a church school.
我明白 但我不负责招生
I appreciate that, Tony, but I'm not involved with admissions.
我就是想跟你聊聊...
I just figured maybe I can come talk to you...
看你是不是要些球员
seeing as though you might need some players.
- 他平常玩什么？- 只要是球类都行 孩子很不错
- What kind of sport does he play? - Anything with a ball. The boy's good too.
下周就开学了 你们得等下学期了
Classes start in a week. It'd have to be for next semester.
这我知道 教练
I know what you're thinking, coach.
不过 我有钱
But look here, I got money, all right?
我是城那边威尔森车场的机械师
See, I'm a mechanic at Wilson's Auto, the other side of town.
如果有学生退学或是转学呢？他们是不是就能上了？
Well, look, what if somebody drops out or moves? Could they get in then?
"他们"？你就提到了一个儿子
"They"? You only mentioned one son.
没错 史提芬 但还有另外一个
That's right, Steven. But there's another boy.
- 另外一个男孩？- 没错
- Heh. Another boy?   - Yeah.
大麦 他晚上经常来我家沙发上睡
Big Mike. Sleeps on my couch from time to time.
这也是没办法 他妈妈吸毒
It's a bad deal. You know, his mom's on that crack pipe.
他没有别的亲人了 他也想来试试看
He ain't got nobody else. He just wanted to come along for the ride.
- 他们来了？- 对
- They're here? - Yeah.
小个子是史提芬...
Now, the little one, that's Steven...
大个子那个是...
and the big one...
大麦
Big Mike.
帅
Swish!
麦克 哈哈
Big Mike! Ha-ha.
来啊
Come on.
我的天
Mother of God.
史提芬•汉弥尔顿的简历看起来还行...
MAN: Steven Hamilton's paperwork looks acceptable to me...
我想他能学好 但是另外这个...
and I believe he'll do fine. But this other kid...
- 大麦 - 麦克•欧尔...
- Big Mike. - Michael Oher...
他的材料让人难以相信...
gives us no reason to believe that...
他在我们学校能读好书
based on his records, that he would be successful here.
能差到哪里去？
Well, how bad could it be?
材料不足 我们都不知道他几岁了
We're not exactly sure how old he is, due to his lack of records.
智商80 排在后6%
He has a measured IQ of 80, which is sixth percentile.
学分积还不到1 只有0.6
His grade-point average begins with zero, 0.6.
他是个烫手山芋
Everyone passed him along.
每个老师都给他D 这样就可以把麻烦扔给别人
They gave him Ds so they could hand their problem off to the next school.
这孩子很勇敢
He's a brave kid.
他想来这里 想接受高品质的教育\
For wanting to come here, for wanting a quality education.
他想要以往读过的那些三流学校所不能给的教育机会
An education denied him by the poor quality of schools he's attended.
你也知道 他这样的学生都不敢靠近我们这种学校
Most kids with his background wouldn't come within 200 miles of this place.
克顿教练 我们知道你很欣赏这孩子的运动潜质
Coach Cotton, we understand your interest in this young man's athletic abilities.
你要知道 他要是读不好书 连参加运动的机会也不会有
He wouldn't be able to play sports until he got his grades up, any way.
先不说体育
Forget sports.
看看墙上
Look at the wall.
"基督徒" 这可不是随便写上去的
"Christian." We either take that seriously or we paint over it.
你们不是因为体育天赋录取麦克•欧尔
You don't admit Michael Oher because of sports.
你们录取他 因为这么做是对的
You admit him because it's the right thing to do.
人类能力有限  上帝无所不能
同学们 这是新来的麦克•欧尔...
Class, this is Mike Oher...
希望大家欢迎新同学
and he's new here so I expect you all to make him feel welcome.
麦克 找个空位坐
Mike, just take any empty seat.
这份试卷里是上学期科学课...
This is a quiz based on the information...
学过的东西
you learned last year in your science curriculum.
别担心 不打分
Don't worry, it's not gonna be graded.
就是摸摸底
I just wanna see how much information we need to hit again.
知道就答
Just answer whatever you know.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 我可以走了吗？- 嗯
- Can I leave now? - Yeah.
带上书
Take your book.
他为什么一直待在我们家？他会吃光我们的东西
I'm tired of having someone always in our home. I'm tired of him eating all the food.
怎么可能 我要像一个基督徒那样对待他 知道吗?
Look, man, you gotta be Christian about this thing.
基督徒让别人当去
Let somebody else be Christian about this thing.
你想让我把他当狗一样赶出去？
Dee, come on, I can't kick him out on the street like he's some dog.
让别人去管他
Let somebody else take the responsibility.
那我怎么办 赶他出去？
What, you want me to go to Beale Street and drop him off?
我不管 我只想跟你在一起
When do I have time just to be with you?
好吧好吧 说不过你 我会处理的
All right, all right. Whatever. You win. I'll take care of it.
我才不管派翠克•拉姆齐喜不喜欢那张椅子的设计
I don't care if Patrick Ramsey approved the chair.
他是联盟的四分卫 而不是什么玛莎•史都尔特
He's an NFL quarterback, not Martha fricking Stewart.
班尼•威廉姆斯怎么可以和La-Z-Boy相提并论
Because there is a difference between Bunny Williams and a La-Z-Boy.
不 当MTV去采访他家的时候...
No, see, when MTV Cribs comes to his house...
他肯定要显摆他的家庭影院
he'll be showing off his home theater.
我必须看到一张棕色的按摩椅
All I'm gonna see is a brown Barcalounger.
不 你听我说 我是设计师 我的名字在上面
No, listen to me, I'm the designer, my name is on it.
照我说的做 明白吗？谢谢
Deliver what I ordered, all right? Thank you.
耶
Yeah.
- 我错过什么了吗？- 柯林斯刚救了个球
- What'd I miss?      - Collins just got a dig.
妈 这是女子排球 你能错过什么
It's girls' volleyball, Mom. You didn't miss anything.
哦
Oh.
- 动起来 柯林斯 快 - 好样的 柯林斯
- Come on, Collins, move your feet. - Good job, Collins.
继续
Go.
柯林斯 我们在外面等你
We'll wait for you outside.
洗澡别太久 回去还要做作业
Don't double condition in the shower, you have homework.
我要去卡农家学习
I'm going to Cannon's to study.
小肖 小肖 别再去女生更衣室了 过来小肖 过来
SJ! SJ, do not go in the girls' locker room again. Come here! SJ, come here!
大个子来了有...一个月了？
The big kid's been here for, what, a month?
还是没有融入我的课程
He's still not cutting it in my class.
为什么要招他？这对他 对我们都不公平
Why does Admissions do this? I mean, it's not fair to us or the boy.
好像就想看他笑话
They're just setting him up to fail.
我想他都不明白我在教什么
I don't think he has any idea of what I'm teaching.
你怎么知道他听明白没 他都不开口
And how would you know if he did? He won't even talk.
他会写字
He writes.
偶尔写他的名字罢了
His name. Barely.
我在垃圾篓里捡到的
He threw this in the trash can.
"我周围都是白色
"I look and I see white everywhere:
白墙 白地板 好多白人
White walls, white floors, and a lot of white people.
老师们不知道 其实我根本听不懂
The teachers do not know I have no idea of anything they are talking about.
我不想听人说话 尤其是老师
I do not wanna listen to anyone, especially the teachers.
他们布置作业 希望我自己能搞定
They are giving homework and expecting me to do the problems on my own.
我可从没做过作业
I have never done homework in my life.
我走到洗手间 看着镜子说
I go to the bathroom, look in the mirror and say:
'这不是麦克•欧尔'"
'This is not Michael Oher.'"
他起的题目是"白墙"
He entitled it "White Walls."
有错别字吗？
How's the spelling?
嗨
Hi.
对他们笑 这样他们就知道你的好意
Smile at them. It lets them know you're their friend.
你是大麦 对吧？
You're Big Mike, right?
我是肖恩
Well, I'm Sean.
但是人们叫我小肖 就是小肖恩的意思 我爸爸的名字是肖恩
But everyone calls me SJ. It's for Sean Junior. My father's name is Sean.
肖恩•图伊？
Sean Tuohy?
他在密西西比大学的时候是篮球明星 后卫
He was a basketball star at Ole Miss, point guard.
他现在是数百万家塔克钟连锁餐厅的老板
Now he owns like a million Taco Bells.
回头见
Adios.
- 你跟谁说话 小肖？- 大麦
- Who is that, SJ?     - Big Mike.
脚拿下来
Get your feet off my dash.
谢谢 系上安全带
Thank you. Put on your seat belt.
大麦？
Big Mike?
麦克 警察局给我打电话
Mike, I got a call from someone at the police department.
你记不记得前阵子报纸上有说一名男子...
You remember a story in the papers a while back about a man who...
坠落天桥？
fell off an overpass?
没人知道他是谁
No one knew who he was.
是不是自己跳下去的 或是...
They didn't know if he jumped or if...
总之他去世了
Well, anyway, he... He passed away.
麦克 他是你父亲
Mike, that man was your father.
警方一直想联系到家属...
They've been looking for somebody to notify and they...
后来他在我们这找到了你的名字
They found your name in our registry.
很遗憾 孩子
I'm really sorry, son.
你和他亲近吗？
Were you close to him?
最后一次见到他是什么时候？
When's the last time you saw him?
不记得
I don't know.
- 他明白 - 你说谁？明白什么？
- He knows it! - Who knows it and what does he know?
这些材料 麦克•欧尔 我今天给他做口头测试
The material. Michael Oher. I gave him this test verbally.
- 还可以这样？- 给他C了？很勉强吧？
- Is that even allowed?    - A "C"? On how big a curve?
他一直在听我讲 他真的听进去了
He's been listening all along. It's amazing what he's absorbed.
相信我 他也有在听你们讲课 他阅读能力很差
And, trust me, he's listening to you too. Now, his reading level is low...
也不知道如何在课堂上学习
and he's got no idea how to learn in a classroom...
我没说他能及格 但大麦不傻
I'm not saying he's gonna pass, but Big Mike is not stupid.
- 嘿 干得好 - 妈  爸
- Hey. Good job. - Mama. Daddy.
演得很好 嘿...
Good job. Hey...
- 我有个问题问你 - 说
- I got a question for you. - Yeah?
你后面两排那个小女孩 她叫什么名字?
There was a little girl about two rows back. What was her name?
- 噢 你说金赛 - 金赛 嗯
- Oh, that was Kinsey. - Kinsey, yeah.
我看你头上的羽毛都乱了
I saw your little Indian feathers get all ruffled up.
嗯 她人不错
Yeah! She is nice.
小肖 别往心里去...
SJ. Don't let this go to your head...
不过我觉得你扮演这个角色还是很合适的...
but I thought you were very convincing in the role of...
- 印第安人三号头目？- 没错
-Indian Number 3?     - Yes.
我也想当酋长 不过他们让孙安迪当了
I tried out for the chief, but they gave it to Andy Sung.
我觉得 这算不算是一种对外来文化的偏好
I can't be sure, but I think there's some multi-cultural-bias thing working.
也许他们只是觉得他当酋长更合适
Or maybe they just thought that he'd make a better chief.
爸 他可是中国人
Dad, he's, like, Chinese.
你还是爱尔兰人呢
Yeah, and you're Irish.
不过既然你不是酋长 这头饰你怎么搞到的？
If you weren't the chief, how did you get the headdress?
爸 再给我几张炸玉米粉饼的赠券
Dad, I'm gonna need a few more of those free quesadilla tickets.
有其父必有其子啊
And where does the acorn fall?
别笑 没那些赠券我们可就裱子了
Hey, don't laugh too hard. The quesadillas saved our ass.
别说脏话
Don't use the A-word.
他就穿这么点？
What is he wearing?
天这么冷
It's freezing.
- 他叫什么来着？- 大麦
- What's his name again? - Big Mike.
他要去哪里？
Where is he going?
嗨 大麦 你去哪里？
Hey, Big Mike. Where you headed?
体育馆
Gym.
去吧
Go ahead.
掉头
Turn around.
大麦
Big Mike!
停车
Stop the car.
大麦
Big Mike.
我叫莉•安妮•图伊 我的孩子也在温盖特中学读书
Hey. My name's Leigh Anne Tuohy. My kids go to Wingate.
你说你去体育馆？
You said you were going to the gym?
学校体育馆都关门了
School gym's closed.
你为什么现在去？
Why were you going to the gym?
大麦？为什么现在去？
Big Mike, why were you going to the gym?
因为...那里暖和
Because it's... It's warm.
你今晚有地方住吗？
Do you have anyplace to stay tonight?
你敢骗我
Don't you dare lie to me.
又是这表情 又要来她那一套了
I've seen that look many times. She's about to get her way.
来吧
Come on.
过来
小肖 往旁边坐
SJ, make room.
上车
Get inside.
快点
Come on.
- 去哪里？- 回家
- Where we going? - Home.
天 我最喜欢这一段了 好可爱
I know, it's my favorite part. He's so cute.
傻小子演戏演得怎么样？
How'd the dork do in the school play?
呃...
Um...
好吧
Okay.
柯林斯 你认识大麦同学吗？
Collins, do you know Big Mike from school?
本可以给你客卧的 不过里面都是箱子
I'd give you the guest bedroom, but it's full of sample boxes.
家庭房里的组合沙发 睡上去就容易滑动
And the sectional in the family room slides apart when you sleep on it.
至少肖恩是这么说的
Least that's what Sean says.
图伊先生睡沙发？
Mr. Tuohy sleeps on the couch?
犯错误的时候才那样
Only when he's bad. All right.
盥洗室在那里 我们在楼上 有事叫我们 行吧？
The powder room is right there and we will be upstairs if you need us. All right?
好吧 睡个好觉 孩子
Okay. Sleep tight, honey.
这样是不是不好？
Was this a bad idea?
什么？
What?
别躺在那儿 装着好像跟我不在想同一件事
Don't lie there and pretend like you're not thinking the same thing as me.
好吧 告诉我你在想什么 然后我就知道该想什么
Tell me what you're thinking so I'll know what's supposed to be on my mind.
你了解大麦吗？
How well do you know Big Mike?
你看他都不怎么说话
Case you hadn't noticed, he didn't have much to say.
有什么大不了？不就一晚上吗？
What's the big deal? It's just for one night, right?
就一晚上吧 莉•安妮？
It is just for one night, right, Leigh Anne?
他应该不会偷东西吧？
You don't think he'll steal anything, do you?
明早就知道了
I guess we'll know in the morning.
（说到密西西比州和阿肯色州）
(talking about Mississippi and Arkansas.)
（现在比赛变得更加有趣了）
(And now the fight's gotten more interesting.)
要是听到惊叫就打给保险公司
Well, if you hear a scream, call the insurance adjuster.
麦克？
Mike?
大麦？
Big Mike?
麦克？
Mike?
大麦
Big Mike!
你非要等我走过来？
You gonna make me walk the whole way?
好吧
All right, then.
你去哪里？
Where are you going?
不知道
I don't know.
那你要和家人过感恩节？
Well, are you spending Thanksgiving with your family?
（这些从州里来的四五十个人可以让他们安静）
(Those 40  50 guys from State here can quiet them down.)
正如你注意到密西西比州防守...
As you mentioned  the Mississippi State defensive...
- 来吃吧 孩子们 - 太好了
- Come and get it, y'all. - Yeah, baby!
我们吃吧
Let's eat!
快点
Come on!
看 有火鸡
It's that Rebel turkey.
大家要谢谢妈妈开车从商店把它带回家
Thank your mother for driving to the store and getting this.
- 谢谢妈妈 - 谢谢妈妈
- Thank you, Mama. - Thank you, Mama.
- 比赛真烂 - 随便吃
- Food and football. - Eat all you want.
来吧 快点 快点 回去看比赛
Come on. Hustle, hustle. We gotta get back over there.
好啊
Going, Dad.
别占我的位子
Don't take my spot.
- 别急啊 小肖 坐下 小肖 - 借过
- No rushing, SJ. SJ, slow down. - Coming through.
- 不 - 太棒了
- No. - This is fantastic.
你们都忘了土豆沙拉 密西西比大学比得怎样？
Oh, y'all, I forgot the potato salad. How's Ole Miss doing?
攻势凌厉
They're kicking butt.
-（一个优秀的接球手离开...） - 不错 是吧？
- (One wide receiver left...)    - Good  huh?
（同时在角落里 30号球员出局 在压力范围...）
(and one corner  number 30  out in press coverage...)
肖恩 沙拉
Sean, salad.
- 谢谢妈妈 - 噢 太好了 谢谢妈妈
- It's great, Mom. - So good. Thanks, Mama.
太好了 妈妈
Yeah, Mama.
（小范围进攻不错 但是内线跑动太少）
(Nice little surge, but not much running inside.)
上啊
Come on.
（防守方取得第三长）
(And the Rebels got third and long here.)
（伯德桑和莫威尼在防守）
(Birdsong and Mawhinney on the tackle.)
（奥利在第三轮中的10球中失手5球）
(Ole miss  five of 10 on third downs.)
（从26降到第三 六个二进制在这里）
(From the 26  third down and six for the Rebs here.)
加油 防守
Come on, defense.
（我认为 雨很慢 让我们看看他们是否尝试通过）
(I formation. The rain is slow  let's see if they try a pass or not.)
（现在 特纳在后场开始动起来了）
(Now Turner goes in motion out of the backfield.)
（斯泰特向曼宁闪电般传球）
(State showing blitz  Manning to throw.)
（跑到了他的右边 把球抛到...）
(Runs to his right throws it at the feet of the...)
- 嗨 妈妈 - 什么？
- Hey. Mom. - What?
今天感恩节啊
But it's Thanksgiving.
- 喔 - 为什么要进来？
- Wow. - Why are we eating in here?
要不要祷告？
Shall we say grace?
天上的父 我们感谢你带给我们家的祝福
Heavenly Father, we thank you for all the many blessings on this family.
我们感谢你给我们带来了新朋友
We thank you for bringing us a new friend.
希望你在节日里眷顾我们
And we ask that you look after us on this holiday season...
这份幸运我们永不忘怀 阿门
that we may never forget how very fortunate we are. Amen.
阿门
Amen.
- 小肖 比分多少？- 直落十分
- Let's check the score. - Up by 10.
柯林斯 把四季豆给我 好吗？
Collins, can you pass me the green beans, please?
用勺子不要用手 用...用...用...
Don't pick it with your fingers. Just take... Take a sp... Ta...
- 小肖 手放下去 - 对不起
- SJ, elbows.   - Sorry.
大麦 想逛街吗？
So, Big Mike. You like to shop?
明天我要教教你
Because tomorrow I think I'm gonna have to show you how it's done.
我有衣服
I got clothes.
你只是有而已
You have clothes.
你就袋子里一件换洗T恤
And an extra T-shirt in a plastic bag does not a wardrobe make.
我有衣服
I have clothes.
那好吧 我们去取 你带路
Fine, let's go get them. Just tell me where I'm going.
好吧
All right.
把你的一切告诉我 我得了解你 谁照顾你 妈妈？
Tell me everything I need to know about you. Who takes care of you? A mother?
你跟母亲住一起？还是奶奶？
Do you have a mother? A grandmother maybe?
告诉你大麦 你要是不肯开口 我一样有办法
Tell you what, Big Mike, we can do this the easy way or we can do this the hard way.
你自己选了
You take your pick.
好吧
Fine.
就告诉我一件事 就一件
Tell me just one thing I should know about you. Just... Just one.
我不喜欢别人叫我大麦
I don't like to be called Big Mike.
好
Okay.
那从现在起 叫你麦克
Tell you what, from now on, to me, you're Michael.
好吧？
Okay?
那么 麦克...
So, Michael...
我们现在怎么走？
where are we headed?
# 我是孩子 你们不是 #
# I kid y'all not  y'all. #
# 我会告诉它让天下雨 一切都好吗？#
# I'm gonna tell it. Make it rain and everything  right? #
萨维... 萨维在杆顶端 她这女人...
Shorty... Shorty gets to the top of the pole. She just done...
- 好车 - 是啊 看
- That's nice. MAN - Yo, check it.
- 那是什么 7？- 还真是
- What's that, a seven? - For real.
- 嗯 - 喜欢吗？
- Yeah. - You like it?
嗯 就在那
Yeah, right there.
- 认识他们吗？- 不认识 哥们
- You know them? - Man, I ain't got no idea, shorty.
你妈妈住在这里？
This is where your mother lives?
- 我们去拿衣服 - 不... 别出去
- Let's go get them. - Don't... Don't get out.
那谁帮你拿衣服 麦克？
Who's gonna help you carry your clothes, Michael?
别下车
Don't get out the car.
不是吧
Snowflake.
原来是大麦
Oh. That's Big Mike, man.
大麦回来了
Oh, Big Mike is in the house.
大麦 你去哪里了？
Big Mike! Where you been, baby?
开车带你的美女是谁 黛茜小姐？
Hey, who that fine thing you got driving you around now, like Miss Daisy or something?
你好 戴夫
Hey, David.
我得给你买双新球鞋了 我会照顾好你的 哥们
You need to holler at me about them sneakers, man. I'm gonna take care of you.
这整个村子都是我的地盘 明白吗 宝贝？
I run this over here in Hurt Village. Baby, believe that.
- 嘿 - 你好
- Hey. - Hello.
看吧 戴夫 看我表演
Ey. Hey, D, watch this. They always go for the wink, watch this.
给你 亲爱的雪花 呵呵
There you go. Yeah, snowflake. Ha-ha-ha.
喜欢吗？嘿嘿
You like that. Yeah.
（房屋收回通告 勿擅自闯入）
- 那孩子不会听我的 - 她谁的话也不听
- That girl will not listen to me. - She don't listen to nobody.
- 嘿 麦克 - 嗨 大麦
- Hey  Mike. - Hi  Big Mike.
她不在家
She wasn't home.
那我们下次再来
Well, we can come back.
也许她搬到更好的地方去了
She probably moved to a nicer place.
我一直在孟菲斯住 却从没到过这附近
I've been in Memphis my whole life and never been anywhere near here.
- 你会保护好我的吧？- 有我在你放心
- You're gonna take care of me, right? - I got your back.
跟我来
Now just follow me, y'all. Uh-huh.
看看
There we go.
女装也有
Oh, we also got apparel for the ladies.
不过适合他穿的 在这里
But everything we got that'll fit him is right here.
就这些？
This is it?
要是只有这些 为什么外面写着 "加宽加大"？
If this is all you got, why's it say "Big and Tall" on the sign?
加宽加大 他需要的是"特宽特大"
Big and Tall. You need Bigger and Taller.
- 有事叫我 - 谢谢
- Holler if you need me. - Thank you.
有喜欢的吗？
See anything you like?
嗨 我们这儿要啥有啥
Hey, I got just what you're looking for.
我的购物经验是...
Well, one thing I know about shopping is that...
如果买回的衣服你不是特别喜欢就不会去穿它
if you don't love it in the store, you won't wear it.
所以在店里就要看好了
The store's where you like it the best.
买下之前 想想自己穿上去的样子
So before you choose something, think of yourself wearing it.
问问自己 "这还是我吗？"
Say to yourself, "Is this me?"
这件怎样？
What about this one?
这件太花了
Well, this is not atrocious, this...
好吧 你在这边看 我在那边看
No? All right, well, you go look over there and I'll go look over here.
这么多衣服居然都是人造材料
Why would you need this many coats out of plastic?
天啊 这是什么做的？
Good Lord. What is this made out of?
这件？你喜欢？
That's the one? That's the one you like?
好吧
Well, all right, then.
祝你们开心 好好学
Have a great day! Learn something.
才这么一会儿就大惊小怪的
Oh, don't get your panties in a wad.
巴黎最吸引我的就是食物了
The best part about Paris was the food.
他们像我们用肉汁那样用酱油
They use sauce like we use gravy.
- 搞的我一回来就得去健身 - 哦
- I had to join a gym the day I got back. - Oh.
你们有没有去过城那头？
Have y'all spent much time on the other side of town?
- 你说的是哪里？- 阿拉巴马街 赫特村
- Where exactly are you talking about? - Alabama Street, Hurt Village.
赫特村 听起来就怕
Hurt Village? That sounds like a threat.
其实并不远
Not far off.
去那里可能会伤到我
I think it might hurt me to go there.
伤害的只是你的名声吧
It would hurt your reputation to go there.
其实我是从那边来的 不过我很努力 看看现在的我
Actually, I'm from there but didn't mind hard work, and look where I am now.
吃着十八块钱一份的沙拉？
Eating an $18 salad?
不过说实在的 不好吃
And it's a little soggy, to be honest.
莉•安娜 你怎么突然对那里有兴趣？又要搞慈善？
What is this sudden interest in the projects? Another one of your "charities"?
等等 你是在下一盘很大的棋 真厉害
Wait. Project for the projects. Ooh. That's catchy!
钱生钱啊
Y'all  money would raise itself.
算我一份 莉•安妮
Okay. Count me in, Leigh Anne.
- 扔了你的账本吧 - 好
- Break out your checkbooks. - Yes.
小肖 再让你玩两分钟好吧？
SJ, you have two more minutes on that Playbox thing, all right?
别啊 妈
Aw, Mom!
麦克 你想留在这里吗？
Michael, do you wanna stay here?
因为...如果你想待在这里...更久一点的话
I mean, because if you wanna stay here for a while longer...
我可以整理个房间给你
I can find some time to figure out a bedroom for you.
你看看这沙发
I mean, because look at this.
一万块钱呢 都快被你睡塌了
You have practically ruined a $10,000 couch.
想留在这里吗 麦克？
Do you wanna stay here, Michael?
我哪儿也不想去了
I don't wanna go anyplace else.
那好吧
Well, all right, then.
小肖 别玩了
SJ, you better be off that Playbox.
还不到两分钟
That wasn't two minutes.
晚安 图伊太太
Good night, Mrs. Tuohy.
我看麦克的紧急医护连络人写的是我们
I see on the admission that we're Michael's contact for medical emergencies.
这是肖恩上周写的
Sean wrote that in last week.
要有点什么事 总得能联系上谁
We needed a contact number and the ones listed weren't in service.
肖恩 我真爱死他了
I love that man.
这是什么？
What's this?
八年级的时候 州政府对所有学生统一做的职业倾向测试...
The state makes schools measure for career aptitude in the eighth grade...
- 他的材料里面带着的 - 麦克怎样？
- and this just came with his file. - What's it say about Michael?
空间关系 后3%
Spatial relations, third percentile.
学习能力 后5%
Ability to learn, fifth percentile.
不过有意思的是 有一项测试 他排在前2%
It's funny though. He tested in the 98th percentile in one category.
- 什么？- 保护意识
- Which one? - Protective instincts.
这边是桌子 衣柜还有抽屉...
So over here you have a desk, chest of drawers...
床头柜 灯 还有闹钟
you have a nightstand, a light, an alarm.
肖恩说专业运动员如果找不到合适的大床 就会用日式床垫
Sean says all pro athletes use futons if they can't find a bed big enough...
所以我给你也买了一个 我不喜欢木架床
so I got you one of those. Of course the frame was heinous.
我们家都没有买过 我给你挑了一种更好的
I was not about to let that in my house, but I got you something nicer.
- 这是我的？- 没错
-It's mine? - Yes, sir.
- 怎么了？- 以前没有过
- What? - Never had one before.
什么？没有自己的房间？
What, a room to yourself?
自己的床
A bed.
那你现在有了
Well, you have one now.
解释一下渗透
Okay. Define osmosis.
我想我知道
I think I know that one.
就是水流过障碍物的时候
It's when water passes through a barrier.
基本正确 麦克 很好
That's basically right, Michael. Very good.
说一个滑铁卢战役中参战者的名字
Name the combatants in the Battle of Waterloo.
我记得一个 嗯...
I know that one. Um...
- 小个子 拿破仑 - 嗯嗯
- The little guy, Napoleon. - Uh-huh.
- 他是一方 公爵是另一方  - 威灵顿公爵
- He was on one side and a duke was on the other.     - Duke of Wellington.
对 威灵顿公爵和俄国还是那里是一伙的
Yeah, and the Duke of Wellington, he had Russians helping him.
普鲁士
Prussians.
别老穿这种衣服了 你看起来就像只大蜜蜂
Enough with the rugby shirts. You look like a giant bumblebee.
那家塔克钟店
That Taco Bell.
肯德基 下个街区的海克兹
KFC catty-corner. And the Long John Silver's on the next block.
都是你们家开的？
You own all of them?
- 对 我们有几百家 - 八十五家
- Yeah. We've got like hundreds. - Eighty-five.
所以 图伊先生不用工作？
Is that why Mr. Tuohy don't have to go to work?
嗨 我无时无刻不在工作好不好
Whoa, whoa! Hey! I'm working even when I'm not working.
- 什么？- 那你们在那些地方吃饭都不要钱？
- What?    - And you eat at all these places for free?
随便吃 棒极了
All you want. It's awesome.
那餐厅每天剩下的菜怎么办？
What do y'all do with all the leftover food from the restaurant?
有些得倒掉 比如已经煮好的那些
We have to throw some out, what's already cooked.
- 太浪费了 - 是啊 我也希望能卖掉
- That's too bad. - Yeah, I'd rather sell it.
你是不是可以把剩菜送人？
Seems like you could give it away or something.
- 你应该考虑下 爸 - 好的 小肖
- You should check into that, Daddy. - All right, I will, SJ.
那我们今晚为什么不在你的饭店里吃饭？
How come we're not eating at one of your restaurants tonight?
- 因为今晚很特别 - 什么？
- Well, because tonight is a special occasion. - What?
我跟克顿教练谈过 他说麦克的成绩已经提高不少...
I talked to Coach Cotton. He said Michael's grades have improved enough...
可以参加三月的春季赛了
that he can go out for spring football in March.
- 是不是很棒？- 哥们 你可以去撞人了
-Isn't that great? - Oh, man! You're gonna crush some people!
- 几位好 - 谢谢
- Hey, guys, how we doing? - Great, thank you.
我要去买一本设计书 肖恩 去看看定位的情况
I've got a design book I need to get. Why don't you check our reservation?
我们去了马上就有位子 你就不能等到饭后再去？
They'll seat us right away. Can't it wait after diinner?
那时候也许就关门了 来吧小肖
They might be closed by then. Come on, SJ!
我要买些新的杂志
I need some new magazines.
麦克 来啊 快
Michael, come on. Come on.
柯林斯 柯林斯
Collins? Collins?
柯林斯 快点 你爸爸要不高兴了 走吧 快
Collins, come on, your dad's already PO'd. Let's go. Come on.
在这里
Over here.
记得这本书吗？你给我们念了无数次了
You remember this one, Morn? You read it to us like a thousand times.
"他咬牙切齿 大声狂吼"
"He gnashed his terrible teeth and he roared his terrible roar."
我一直很喜欢这个故事
I always liked this one.
噢 斐迪南
Mm. Ferdinand.
我也喜欢
Me too.
麦克 你妈妈有没有给你读过这些书？
Michael, your mama ever read either one of those books to you?
没有？
No?
多可爱
How cute
牛排不错
It was a good steak, huh?
谢谢 爸爸
Thank you, Daddy.
谢谢这顿美食 爸爸
Thank you for a lovely dinner  Papa.
走吧
Here we go.
麦克 你刚才在饭店跟谁说话呢?
Michael. Who was that boy you were talking to at the restaurant?
马库斯
Marcus.
- 马库斯 他在那里工作？- 嗯
- Marcus, and he... He works there? - Yeah.
你怎么认识他的？
How do you know him?
他是我哥
He's my brother.
那我们哪天得认识认识
Well, we'd really... We'd really like to meet him someday.
你觉得合适吗？
Would that be okay with you?
我不知道他住在哪里
I don't know where he stays.
你上次见到他是什么时候？
When was the last time you saw him?
很小的时候吧
When I was little, maybe.
"从前呢 在西班牙 有一只小牛...
"Once upon a time in Spain, there was a little bull...
叫费迪南
and his name was Ferdinand.
他的朋友们总是跑跑跳跳...
All the other little bulls he lived with would run and jump...
互相撞头
and butt their heads together.
但斐迪南不会
But not Ferdinand.
他就喜欢安静地坐着 闻着花香
He liked to sit just quietly and smell the flowers.
他喜欢坐在牧场上的软木树下
He had a favorite spot out in the pasture under a cork tree.
那棵树他最喜欢了
It was his favorite tree...
他会整天坐在树荫下 闻着花香"
and he would sit in its shade all day and smell the flowers."
- 晚安 - 晚安
- Good night. - Good night.
- 什么？- 怎么？
- What? - What?
为什么笑？
Why are you smiling?
不知道 高兴吧 真的高兴
I don't know, I'm just happy. Real happy.
这跟麦克有关系吗？
Does this happiness have anything to do with Michael?
不
No.
都是因为他
It has everything to do with Michael.
嗯嗯
Mm. Mm.
- 高兴是好事 - 嗯
- Happy's good. - Mm.
你知道我们该干嘛吗？
You know what I think we should do?
我们应该为像麦克那样的孩子搞个慈善活动
We should start a charity for kids like Michael.
- 好 - 也许在温盖特中学资助一个计划
- Okay.     - Maybe fund a program at Wingate.
没问题
Sure.
上帝也希望那个学校能有黑人同学
Lord knows that school could use a little color.
麦克给那个地方带去了新鲜空气
Poor Michael's like a fly in the milk in that place.
你有在听我说吗？
Are you listening to me?
- 嗯 - 我努力一次...注意...一件事情
- Hmm? - I try to concentrate on one...thing...at a time.
你娶我的时候就知道我会一心多用 对吧？
You knew I was a multitasker...when you married me, right?
- 当然 - 那好吧 我只是确认一下
- I sure did. - Right. Okay, just checking.
好的 图伊一家 大家笑得灿烂点
Okay, Tuohy family. Big smiles, everyone.
一 二 三
And one, two, three!
麦克
Michael.
麦克 下一张你也来
Michael. Come on down here and get in the next one.
来啊 来这里
Come on. Come on. Come on down.
别这样 我又不会拿这张放在圣诞贺卡上
Oh, come on. It's not like I'm gonna put it on the Christmas card.
好 大家挤一挤
Okay, let's scootch in a little tighter.
很好
That's good.
灿烂点
Really big smiles.
好 一 二 三
Okay, one, two, three.
- 说"茄子"   - 茄子
- Say "Rebels!"      - Rebels!
（一道闪电从角落快速穿越过中间...）
(a blitz off the corner  quick pass over the middle...)
知道了
I got it.
- 哪边领先？- 田纳西
- Who's winning? - Tennessee.
- 他们对谁？- 科雷姆森
- Ugh. Who they playing? - Clemson.
不管对谁 你妈妈都站在田纳西的另一边？
Your mama roots against Tennessee no matter who they play?
额...没错 个人偏好
Uh... Yes, I do. With gusto.
她受不了田纳西
She can't stand Tennessee.
柯林斯 我以为你要去你男朋友那里？
Collie-bell, I thought you were going over to your boyfriend's.
我今天还是在家吧
Thought I'd hang around here for the day.
嗯
Hmm.
我喜欢
I like that.
亲爱的 答录机有几条留言我还没听
There's a couple messages on the machine. I didn't check them.
好吧
All right.
肖恩 莉•安妮 我是鲍比表哥 祝你们新年好
Hey, Sean, hey, Leigh Anne, it's your cousin Bobby. Happy New Year's.
- 这卡片上有五个人... - 你没看错
- Listen, I've had about five cold ones... - Of course you have.
所以我特地打来问一下
so I'm just gonna go ahead and ask
你没发现上面有一个黑人小孩？
Did y'all know there's a colored boy in your Christmas card?
怎么？
What?
在他身旁你看上去好小一只 对吧？
You just looked teeny-tiny next to him.
就像洁西嘉•兰格和金刚在一起
Right? Like Jessica Lange and King Kong.
麦克 去塔克钟是不是也有内部优惠？
Hey, does Michael get the family discount at Taco Bell?
是的话 估计肖恩有几家店要关门了
Because if he does, Sean's gonna lose a few stores.
他是个好孩子
He's a good kid.
我看不如正式领养他得了
Well, I say you make it official and just adopt him.
再过几个月他就18岁了 办领养手续也没太大意义
He's gonna be 18 in a few months. Doesn't really make much sense to legally adopt.
莉•安妮
Leigh Anne.
这是不是又是你那什么作为白人的内疚感？
Is this some sort of white-guilt thing?
你爸爸要知道了会怎么说？
What will your daddy say?
你是说去世前还是去世后？
Um... Before or after he turns over in his grave?
伊莱恩 我父亲走了五年了
Daddy's been gone five years, Elaine.
但我还是忘不了你在葬礼上的装束 记得吗？
Make matters worse, you were at the funeral. Remember?
香奈尔 还有那可怕的黑帽
You wore Chanel and that awful black hat.
听着 这么着
Look, here's the deal.
我不需要你们来认可我的做法 好吗？
I don't need y'all to approve my choices, all right?
但起码尊重我的选择 你们不知道这孩子经历过什么事
But I do ask that you respect them. You have no idea what this boy's been through.
你们要是再这么冷嘲热讽...
And if this is gonna become some running diatribe...
我可以在我家附近另找一家这么贵的沙拉店
I can find an overpriced salad a lot closer to home.
- 莉•安妮 很抱歉 我们不是故意... - 对 真的不是
- Leigh Anne, I'm sorry. We didn't intend to... - No, we didn't, really.
我觉得你这么做真的很棒...
I think what you're doing is so great.
你向他开放了你家
To open up your home to him?
亲爱的 你改变了这孩子的生活
Honey, you're changing that boy's life.
不
No.
他改变了我的生活
He's changing mine.
真好 不过科林斯呢？
And that's awesome for you, but what about Collins?
-克林斯 怎么了？- 你就没担心吗?
- What about Collins?    - Aren't you worried?
哪怕只有一点？
I mean  even just a little?
他是个男孩 这么大块头 还是黑人 睡在一个屋檐下
He's a boy, a large, black boy, sleeping under the same roof.
真为你感到羞耻
Shame on you.
这个我拿走了
I've got this.
老实跟我讲
Be honest with me, okay?
麦克住在我们家 你会不会觉得不自在？
Does Michael being here make you uncomfortable?
别管那些傻孩子的胡言乱语
They're stupid kids. Who cares what they say?
- 什么孩子？- 同学
- What kids? - At school.
他们太幼稚了
They're juvenile.
那些幼稚的同学说什么了？
And what do the juvenile kids say?
真的没必要再提
It's really not worth repeating.
也别担心小肖
And don't worry about SJ.
他喜欢别人关注 他向别人介绍麦克都说是自己大哥
He likes all the attention. He introduces Michael as his big brother.
那你呢？
And what about you?
没事啦
It's fine.
你总不能把他踢回街上吧？
I mean, you can't just throw him out on the street.
我可以安排其他办法
I could make other arrangements.
- 你好 麦克 - 你好 要帮你推一下吗？
- Hi, Mike. - Hi. Need a push?
好
Yes.
- 呜 - 再高点 麦克 再高点
- Oh.   - Higher, Mike, higher!
再高点
Higher!
别往下看 别往下看
Don't look down, don't look down. Ah!
- 你去哪里？- 柯林斯？
- Where are you going?     - Collins?
别老这么看着我
Quit looking at me like that.
我们在家不也是一起做功课吗
I mean, we study together at home.
知道那些东西有多重吗？这孩子会让我们出名
You know how much those things weigh? This kid's gonna make us all famous.
别激动 伯特 这才春天呢 他还没正式开始训练
Easy, Bert, man. It's only the spring. He hasn't even had his first practice yet.
不 他绝对有天赋
No, he's a player.
准备好
Ready.
蹲下 孩子 在你的位子上蹲下 在你的位子上!
Get down, son. Get down in your stance. In your stance!
开始
Go!
麦克 孩子 阻挡的时候 要用推
Mike, son, you... You fought off the block...
像剥皮那样
then you wanna shuck the blocker.
知道吗？推 好 开始
All right? Shuck him. All right, let's go.
准备开始
Huddle up.
爸
Papa.
他怎样？
How's he doing?
还没怎么入门
Hasn't quite gotten the hang of it yet.
麦克 孩子
Mike, son.
推他 不要抱住他
Shuck the blocker, don't tote him!
准备 开始
Set go
不不不不不不
No, no, no! No, no, no!
准备 开始
Set go
气球 气球而已
Balloons! They're balloons!
伙计们 别再看气球了
Guys, quit looking at the balloons. Everybody!
大多数孩子处境不利的时候都会很暴力...
Most kids from bad situations can't wait to be violent...
在场上也一样
and that comes out on the field.
但他好像不想攻击别人
But this kid, he acts like he doesn't wanna hit anyone.
他是小牛 斐迪南
He's Ferdinand the Bull.
- 什么？- 没事
- What? - Nothing.
我以为他很有天赋
I thought he was gonna be a player.
我当时可是用尽全身解数才让他进了学校
I can't believe I used up all my chips to get him in school.
你不是说那是基督徒的责任
I thought you said it was your Christian duty.
听着伯特 他以前都没玩过
Look, Bert, he's never even played before.
他要是没什么进步 秋赛也就别想玩了
Yeah, and he won't this fall if he doesn't improve a lot before then.
见过这样当教练的？
Who died and made him Bear Bryant?
难以置信
Unbelievable.
噢 上帝保佑我
Oh, God bless me.
这是你暑假的训练计划
This is your summer workout sheet.
上面说要先热身 放松
Now, first it says to warm up and get loose.
来吧 放松
Well, go ahead, get loose.
松了？
Are you loose?
好 接下来五个一百米跑 就当是拉腿了
Okay. Next, it's five 100-yard runs to stretch out your legs.
- 我们还是回家打电动吧 - 听着
- Can we just go home and play video games? - Look!
温盖特的每个人都期待你成为橄榄球明星
Everybody at Wingate is expecting you to be a star football player.
你不会让他们失望吧？
Don't wanna let them down, do you?
- 不知道 - 那爸爸妈妈呢?
- I don't know. - What about Dad and Mom?
你看 我们家每个人都是运动员
Because, you see, in our family, everyone's an athlete.
爸爸是篮球明星 柯林斯 打排球 竞走
Dad was a basketball star. Collins plays volleyball and runs track.
我呢 你也知道 全能
And me, well, as you know, I do it all.
妈妈...妈妈是啦啦队员
And Mom... Well, Mom was a cheerleader...
所以其实不算数 不过别跟她说 好吗？
which doesn't exactly count, but don't tell her I said that. Okay?
- 好 - 好
- Okay. - Okay.
嗯 50  51
Yeah. Fifty. Fifty-one.
52  53
Fifty-two. Fifty-three.
快点 你能抓住他 快 快 快 加油
Come on, you can get him. Go, go, go! Come on!
只剩五秒钟了
Five seconds left in the game!
这边
This way!
膝盖抬高 膝盖抬高 跑快点!
High knees, high knees, high knees! Speed kills, baby! Run like the wind!
快点 麦克 快
Go, Michael, go!
98  99
Ninety-eight. Ninety-nine.
One hundred.
动起来 动起来 快 快 上
Move your feet, move your feet! Come on, come on! Go!
- 快点 - 啊
- There you go. - Ahh
追上去 快 快 快
You gotta get the tackle, come on, come on, come on!
来 麦克
Come on, Michael.
图伊太太？
Mrs. Tuohy?
一听到 "图伊太太" 我就以为是婆婆来了
I hear "Mrs. Tuohy," I look over my shoulder for my mother-in-law.
叫我 莉•安妮 或者妈妈 或者其他的
Call me Leigh Anne or Mama or almost anything else.
- 能帮我搞个东西吗？- 什么？
- Can you help me get something? - What?
驾照
Driver's license.
你都没有车 要驾照做什么?
Why do you need a driver's license when you don't even have a car?
麦克 你为什么要驾照？
Michael, why do you want a driver's license?
想有个证件带着
It's something to carry with my name on it.
系统里没有叫麦克•欧尔的人
There's no one by the name of Michael Oher in the system.
是不是有别的名字？
Another last name, perhaps?
这样 我签一份文件证明他跟我们住
Look, I will sign something that says he lives with us.
所有的保险我们埋单 可以吗？
We'll pay for all of the insurance. Whatever it takes. Okay?
需要什么手续？
What's it gonna take?
- 你想干嘛？- 你没听错
- You wanna do what? - You heard me.
- 我们不该先谈谈吗？- 现在不是在谈吗？
- Shouldn't we at least talk about this? - What do you think we're doing?
别弄得好像我背着你干什么似的
And don't act like I'm going behind your back.
我知道你去过学校 把麦克的医疗连络人改成了我们
I know you put us down as Michael's medical contact at school.
但为一个人生病买单和为他整个人负责...
There is a huge difference between paying for a broken arm...
完全不是一码事 而且我们都不怎么了解他
and being legally responsible for someone. I mean, a kid we barely know.
这是另一回事 我们得了解他的过去
That's another thing. We need to find out more about his past.
但他不说话 他就跟洋葱一样 你得一层层剥开
He won't talk about it. He's like an onion. You have to peel him back a layer at a time.
但如果有刀就快多了
Not if you use a knife.
要不带他去看青少年心理医生之类的？
What if we took him to a child psychologist or something?
- 你真的想让大麦...  - 是"麦克"
- Do you really expect Big Mike to...?     - Michael.
你真的觉得麦克会躺在那里...
Do you expect Michael to lie on a couch...
像伍迪•艾伦那样把他的童年娓娓道来?
and talk about his childhood like he's Woody Allen or something?
麦克的特长就是遗忘
I mean, Michael's gift is his ability to forget.
他从不生气 也不在意过去发生了什么
He's mad at no one and he really doesn't care what happened in the past.
没错
You're right.
什么？"没错"？
Excuse me? "You're right"?
你居然也会说这种话？
How'd those words taste coming out of your mouth?
是不是觉得酸溜溜的
Like vinegar.
至少答应我考虑一下
Well, at least promise me you'll think about it.
好吧
All right.
"好吧" 是说你会考虑一下
"All right, you'll think about it,"
还是 "好吧" 我们就这么做吧？
or, "All right, we should do it"?
有区别吗？
Is there a difference?
告诉吉罗德梳镜柜的事情 等我回去再说
Just tell Gerald to hold on to the chiffonier and I will be by there after a while.
你别...我回头再打给你
You know... I gotta call you back. Bye.
借过
Excuse me.
我不是插队 就问一句
I'm not cutting, I'm just asking.
我告诉你 我们在这里坐了一个多小时
Let me tell you something. We have been sitting around here for over an hour...
但看看你们不是在吹牛 就是喝咖啡
...and when I look around and all I see are people shooting the bull and drinking coffee.
这地方谁开的？
Who runs this place?
你放心 这两天我暂时不会砸了它
I'd have it in shape in two days, I can tell you that.
- 谅你也不敢 有什么可以帮忙的？- 噢 他先来的
- I bet you would. How can I help you? - Oh, he was first.
- 不 你先 我也想听听你要说什么 - 我也想
- No, you go ahead. I think I wanna hear this. - Me too.
我不喜欢你这态度
I do not appreciate the attitude.
太太 请告诉我你需要什么...
Ma'am, now, you can tell me what you want...
否则你排一天队可别怪我
or I can make sure you wait here all day.
有什么可以帮忙的？
Now, how can I help you?
我想成为法定监护人
I would like to become a legal guardian.
上帝保佑那个孩子
Lord help that child.
关于麦克的资讯很少 大多数文件都不见了
There's very little on Michael. Most of his files have been lost.
- 那里面有什么？- 一些案件记录
- Well, what is in there?   - A few case notes.
这一宗说的是 警官在麦克七岁那年
This one describes an incident where officers forcibly removed Michael...
把他从邓尼斯•欧尔身边强行带走
from Denise Oher's care when Michael was 7.
场面很混乱 孩子们不得不分开
Quite a scene evidently. They had to split up the kids.
- 但这也是下策中的上策了 - 他母亲在哪儿？
- And it's far from the worst. - Where is she? His mother?
不知道 如果你找到她 那就有更多资料了
I don't know. If you find her, we got a heap more files we could add to.
她有几个孩子？
Well, how many kids does she have?
也许有十几个吧
Least a dozen, probably. If not more.
从她吸毒被捕的记录来看估计她自己都数不清楚
With her drug-arrest record, my guess would be, she can't even remember.
我能看看吗？
Can I see that?
所以我们得得到她的许可？
So we would need her permission, right?
不 现在麦克属于被州政府监护
No. Michael is a ward of the state.
只要申请 让法官签署档就行了
Just apply and get a judge to sign off on it.
所以都不用通知他母亲 就可以把他领走？
So you would just give him away without even telling his mother?
核对一下这里
Check out this piece right here.
欧尔太太？
Miss Oher?
你好 欧尔太太？
Hi. Miss... Miss Oher?
- 你是政府的人？- 不是
- You from the state? - No.
我叫莉•安妮•图伊 你儿子...
My name is Leigh Anne Tuohy, and your son...
麦克 跟我住在一起...
Michael, lives with me...
还有我家人
and my family.
孩子怎么样了？大麦怎么样了？
How is my boy? How's Big Mike?
他很好 真的很好
He's fine. He's doing real well.
厨房里可能有些酒 你如果...
We might have some wine in the kitchen, if you...
噢不不 谢谢你了
Oh, no, no. That's real kind.
你最后见到麦克是什么时候？
When did you last see Michael?
不知道
I don't know.
多少...？你有多少个养子？
How many...? How many foster kids you got living with you?
噢 我不是麦克的养母 我们只是在帮他
Oh, I'm not a foster parent to Michael. We're just helping him out.
州政府没给你们什么？
State don't pay you nothing?
没有
No  no.
那你给他吃的穿的？
And you feed him and you buy him clothes too?
嗯 只是没什么合适的衣服
Well, when we can find them in his size.
您真是个善良的基督徒
You are a fine Christian lady.
我尽量做吧
Well, I try to be.
您这是在做善事啊 但是...
This all real nice, what you're doing, but...
不过哪天你醒来见不到他 可别惊讶
don't be surprised if one day you wake up and he gone.
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
他是个 "浪子"
He's a runner.
州政府把他从我身边带走之后就是这么形容他的
That's what the state called him after they took him from me.
就算送到别人家领养...
Every foster home they sent him to...
他还是会半夜溜出来找我
he'd slip out the window at night and come looking for me.
不论我在哪里 那孩子都会找到我 照顾我
No matter where I was, that boy would come find me, take care of me.
我身体不大好
I've had some health problems.
欧尔太太 麦克出生的时候是不是有别的名字？
Miss Oher, was Michael born under a different name?
普罗克特 这是他父亲的名字
Proctor. That was his daddy's last name.
他在哪里？
Where is he?
- 走了之后就再也没见到 - 什么时候的事？
- I ain't seen him since he left. - And when was that?
麦克出生后几周
Week after Mike was born.
你有他的出生证明吗？
Do you happen to have his birth certificate?
没事 我再想办法
It's all right. I'll figure it out.
欧尔太太 你永远是麦克的妈妈
Mrs. Oher, you'll always be Michael's mama.
你想不想见他？
Would you like to see him?
不 不能这样子见他
No. Not this way.
威廉姆斯
It's Williams.
他名字叫威廉姆斯
His last name's Williams.
都不记得这孩子的父亲是谁了
Couldn't even remember who the boy's father is.
那颜色更好 图像更明亮 太棒了
I checked out the new Madden. The colors are better, graphics brighter. It's awesome.
麦克 我们想问你一件事
Michael, we have something we'd like to ask you.
- 什么？- 莉•安妮 和我 我们...
- What? - Well, Leigh Anne and I, we...
我们想成为你的法定监护人
Well, we'd like to become your legal guardians.
那是什么意思？
What's that mean?
意思就是 我们想知道...
What it means is, is that we wanna know...
你是否愿意成为这家庭的一份子？
if you would like to become part of this family.
我以为已经是了
Kind of thought I already was.
那好吧
Well, all right, then.
这边一点
Right here.
- 还有几级台阶 - 小心脚
- You got a couple steps. - Better watch that big foot.
最后一级
One more.
最后一级 到了
One more. There you go.
好吧 拿下来吧
All right. Take off the blindfold.
这就是你想要的吧？
Well? That's the one you wanted, isn't it? Heh.
给你 去吧 试试看 去
Here. Here you go, go ahead. Take it for a ride. Go on.
- 我也能去吗？- 嗯 麦克？小心点
- Can I go too? - Yeah, but, Michael? Be careful.
冲啊
shotgun!
喔喔
Whoo-hoo
- 他想要卡车？- 麦克觉得他是红脖子
- He wanted a truck? - Well, Michael thinks he's a redneck.
来啊 麦克
Come on, Michael!
好 你就是番茄酱 左前锋位置 无球区
Okay. See, you're the ketchup, here at left tackle on the weak side.
第一场很简单 叫"缺口"
The first play is simple. Gap.
看 这些碟子的意思就是 不论你前面是谁都要挡着他...
Now, see, this just means that you're going to block whoever's in front of you...
或者在没有人替你防守的时候 不论你侧面有谁都要拦着
or on your inside shoulder, if you're not covered by a defender.
现在我是跑锋 看看你该怎么打
Now, I'll be the running back, and you show me what you're supposed to do.
预备...开始
Ready? Hike!
拦住他 撞他 四分卫要传球
You'll block him. He'll hit him. Quarterback" hand it off.
他拿到球 然后
He gets the ball  and he takes off
到球门区没障碍了 一击到底
Open lane to the end zone. All there is to it.
怎么了？
What's going on here?
香料刚刚得分了
Blended spice just scored.
我在指导战术 麦克 得打进攻位
We were going through the playbook. Michael got moved to offense.
嗯 搞完了之后 把球员放回到香料柜 谢谢
When you're done, put the players back in the spice cabinet. Thank you.
没问题
No problem.
其实呢妈妈 我们在等你
Actually, Mom, we were kind of waiting for you.
新的麦登橄榄球游戏出来了...
You see, the new Madden game came out...
麦克 和我想去买
and me and Michael were wanting to go get it.
- 不行宝贝 我十分钟后开会 - 但他会开车!
- I can't, I've got a meeting in 10 minutes. - But he can drive.
他可以带我去
He can drive us.
太好了 就想这样
Oh, yeah, that's what I'm talking about.
- 你懂什么？- 我什么都懂
- What you know about this? - I know a lot about this.
- 好 表演给我看看 - 说来就来
- Show me something then. - I'll show you something.
- 我起个头 你跟着我 - 好
- I'll start it. Follow my lead. - All right.
- 准备好了？- 嗯
- You ready? - Yeah.
这可不是四万块钱的奥沙克 大哥
This is not a $40,000 Oushak, Omid.
你也太过分了 莉•安妮
You're crazy, Leigh Anne.
边都不一样宽 被改过了
The borders are different widths. They've been altered.
最多一万七 可以吗？你好?
We'll give you 17, tops, all right? Hello.
喂 女士 你不能进去
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Ma'am, you can't get through.
那是我的孩子们
Those are my kids. Those are my kids.
- 上帝啊 - 上帝啊 让他平安吧
- Oh, my God. - Please, God, let him be okay.
- 他们在哪里？- 对不起 对不起
- Where are they? -  I'm so sorry!
- 麦克 你还好吧？- 我还好 小肖 去看看小肖
- Michael, are you okay? - I'm fine! SJ! Go help SJ!
对不起 对不起
I'm so sorry. So sorry.
他的器官怎么样了？
How are his vitals?
对不起 女士？
- Excuse me, ma'am.
小肖 小肖
SJ. SJ.
- 妈？- 我在 宝贝
- Mama? - Yes, baby.
这血是不是会从我衣服里渗出来？
Do you think the blood'll come out of my shirt?
是的 血应该会渗出来
Yes, I think the blood will come out of your shirt.
女士 气囊在200里以上就会打开
An air bag deploys at 200 miles an hour.
你儿子还太小 不能坐前排
Your son is too small to be in the front seat.
但他不是没事吗？
But he is okay, right?
嘴唇破了 脸擦伤 通常他这么小的孩子撞上气囊...
Busted lip, bruised face. Usually when someone his size gets hit with a air bag...
不是脸变形 就是脖子断 也许更糟
it's a fractured face, broken neck, maybe worse.
好像气囊展开了 但又改变了方向
It's like the air bag was coming for him and changed direction.
可能出了什么毛病...
It's probably defective or something...
你儿子相当走运
but your son's very, very lucky.
不知道 我叫保险公司了 他没事
No, I did. I called the insurance, it's fine. It's fine.
回头再说 先挂了 再见
I'll talk to you later. I gotta go. Bye.
小肖没事
SJ's fine.
他正享受着周围人的注目礼呢
He is. He's actually enjoying all the attention he's getting back there.
喂 麦克 谁都可能碰上 知道吗？不是你的错
Hey, Michael, could've happened to anyone, all right? It's not your fault.
亲爱的 看着我
Honey, look at me.
麦克 你手臂怎么了？
Michael, what happened to your arm?
我拦住了它
I stopped it.
欧尔 你比克里斯重100磅...
Oher! You got 100 pounds on Collie and...
你就不能把他从我们的后场赶走？
you can't keep him out of our backfield?
一直拦住 直到听到哨声 拦住
Hold your block until the whistle blows. Hold it!
好 开始
All right, let's go!
为什么要录影？
What's with the camera?
麦克只要看了 就能做得更好
Michael always does better when he sees what he's supposed to be doing.
- 暂停 左前锋 - 加油啊 麦克
- Holding. Left tackle. - Michael! Come on.
欧尔？
Oher.
过来 孩子
Come here  son.
你得抓住对方 抓住这里 胸口这 明白吗？
If you're gonna hold him, hold him inside here, between the tits. You got it?
你能不能看着我？
Will you look at me, son?
你如果抓的是这里 像刚才那样 就完全是另一码事了...
If you grab him outside here like this or with that horse-collar thing you just did...
我们会犯规 我会很生气 明白吗？
you're gonna get flagged and I'm gonna be pissed, you hear?
好了 开始
All right, let's go!
宝贝 看好我的东西
Baby, watch my stuff, all right?
好
Okay.
至少他的外表能唬住对手
Well, at least he'll look good coming off the bus.
发现他的实力之前 他们会吓坏的
They'll be terrified till they realize he's a marshmallow.
看着像泰山 比赛起来像珍妮
Looks like Tarzan, plays like Jane.
给我一分钟 伯特
Give me a minute, Bert.
- 我们在训练呢  - 你稍后可以再谢我
- We're in the middle of a practice.    - You can thank me later.
过来
Come here.
麦克 你记不记得刚认识的时候 我们去那个可怕的镇子...
Michael. Remember when we first met and we went to that horrible part of town...
买那些破烂衣服？
to buy you those dreadful clothes?
我有点怕 你告诉我别担心 因为有你在
I was a little scared. You told me not to worry, you had my back.
- 记得吗？- 记得 女士
- You remember that? - Yes, ma'am.
如果有人想害我 你会拦住他们 对吧？
And if anyone tried to get to me, you would've stopped them, right?
你和小肖出车祸的时候 你把气囊怎么了?
And when you and SJ were in that car wreck, what did you do to the air bag?
- 拦住了  - 对 你拦住了 是你拦住了
- Stopped it.     - You stopped it. You stopped it.
这队伍就是你的家人 麦克
This team is your family, Michael.
你得保护他们 远离那帮人 知道吗？
You have to protect them from those guys, okay?
听着
Listen.
东尼是你的四分卫 对吧？你保护他的盲点
Okay. Tony here is your quarterback, all right? You protect his blind side.
看到他 你就想我 像保护我一样
When you look at him, you think of me, how you have my back...
保护他 好吧？好 东尼你回去
how you have his. Okay? All right, Tony, go back.
好吧
All right.
欧普萝是你的后卫 看到他 你就想小肖...
Oompa-Loompa here is your tailback. When you look at him, think of SJ...
永远不要让谁伤害到他 明白了吗？
and how you'd never let anyone or anything hurt him. You understand me?
好 回去
All right. Go back.
- 明白了？- 那柯林斯和图伊先生呢？
- Got it?   - What about Collins and Mr. Tuohy?
好吧 他们也在队伍里 你会保护家人吗 麦克?
Fine, they can be on the team too. Are you gonna protect the family, Michael?
- 会的 女士 - 好孩子
- Yes, ma'am. - Good boy.
去玩吧
Now go have some fun.
大声吼没用的 伯特 他不相信别人
Yelling at him doesn't work, Bert. He doesn't trust men.
在他以往的经历里 那些人都装做关心他 但后来都消失了
In his experience, they pretend to care about you till they disappear.
不玩了？
Wanna run a play?
小肖 这次你得好好录
SJ, you're gonna wanna get this.
好
Okay.
加油 麦克
Come on, Michael.
很好麦克 加油
All right, Michael, come on.
- 好样的 麦克 - 很好 很不错
- Whoo! Yes! Michael! - All right, way to go, O, way to go!
帅
Yes!
好孩子
That a boy.
好吧 你跟他说了什么？
Okay. What'd you say to him?
你应该了解你的队员 伯特
You should get to know your players, Bert.
他的保护意识排在前2%
He tested 98 percent in protective instincts.
我说了你可以稍后再谢我
I said you could thank me later.
现在是时候了
It's later, Bert.
看来没有主场优势了
So much for home-field advantage.
你见过这么集中的农民群体吗？
You ever see so many rednecks in one place?
还真没有
NASCAR. Not even close.
十字军 准备好迎接48分钟的炼狱吧
Crusaders! Get ready for 48 minutes of hell!
你屁股真大
Look at that fat ass.
上场吧
Pay them back on the field.
等等 听我说
Corning through. Hold on. Listen up! Listen up!
别被他们干扰 集中注意力 准备好了？
Don't let them get inside your head now. Keep your composure! You ready?
- 是的 - 那好 出发 上
Yeah! - All right, let's go, Crusaders!
- 加油  -  麦克
- Go, Wingate! - Let's go, Crusaders! - Michael!
操 这不公平 他们队伍里有个大屁股
Damn, that ain't fair. They got a big old black bear playing for them.
- 这是马戏团吗？- 没错
- What is this, a circus? - Right.
往前看 小肖 别理他们 别理他们
Eyes forward, SJ. Sticks and stones. Sticks and stones. Come on!
加油
Go
好  好 开局不错
All right, all right. Good start.
- 上啊 上 - 呼
- Let's go, O! Let's go! - Whoo!
嘿 大伙 看看这头大水牛 呜
Hey, you guys, look at this big buck we got right here! Whoo!
弄死你 弄死你
Corning after you! Coming after you!
等着我 等着
You're all mine. All mine.
耶
Yeah
别让他向前 欧尔 加油 孩子
Don't let him rip through, Oher! Come on, son.
- 耶 好小子 今晚有你受的了 大屁股 - 干得好
- Yeah! That's right, boy! All night long, fat ass! All night long! - Good job.
小子 今晚看我不玩死你
I got you, boy! All night long. Whoo-hoo-hoo!
这才是我的好孩子
Now that's my boy.
没事的 麦克
It's all right, Michael.
- 没事 加油 - 加油
- It's all right. Come on. - Let's go.
干掉他们 上
Shake it off. Come on.
准备好 第二轮 伙计 第二轮
Here we go. Round two, baby, round two.
准备
Ready
- 开始 - 交换 交换
- Set! - Switch! Switch!
- 明白 好了 - 上
Got it  Got it - Go.
欧尔 别让他们进到间隙区 加油 动动脑
Oher, don't let him get the inside gap on you. Come on. Use your head!
伯特怎么教的？水准太低了
What is Bert doing? Nothing.
嘿 小胖 我们没完
Hey, fat boy. We're not done yet.
今晚玩死你 玩死你
All game long, boy. All game long!
上
go!
传球 传球 传球
Pass, pass, pass!
不要 唉
Stop this... Oh!
呜呜呜
Whoo-hoo-hoo
耶
Yeah.
为什么不再传球 伯特？
Why another pass, Bert?
你去哪儿 小胖？
Hey, where you going, fat boy?
你最好别再来玩 这里不欢迎你 这是我的地盘
You better stay off my field. You are not welcome here! This is my field!
- 66号 回你自己那边去 - 伯特 闭嘴 伯特
- Sixty-six, get back to your own bench! - Bert! Be quiet. Bert!
喂？
Hello?
别再耍小把戏了 伯特 传球
Enough with the trick plays, Bert. Run the dang ball.
听见没有 传球 传球
You heard me. Run the dang ball. Run it!
等等 他不会挂电话了吧？
Wait, did he just hang up the phone?
- 估计是信号不好 - 怎么可能是信号不好
- No, I think he lost service. - He did not lose service.
- 呜 - 好样的 吉米 66号
- Whoo! - Oh, that's my boy, Jimmy! No.66
玩死他们
Kicking that blue gum's ass.
嘿 大嘴巴
Hey. Crotch-mouth.
说你呢 给我闭嘴 要不老娘上去让你闭嘴
Yeah, you. Zip it or I'll come up there and zip it for you.
不是说不理他们？
Sticks and stones?
你别管 小肖 往前看
You know what, SJ, just turn forward.
继续给我录影 快点
Just pick up the camera and keep shooting. Come on.
拦住它
Squeeze in!
没事 没事 还有机会
It's all right. All right, all right, we can come back from that.
上
go!
加油
Come on!
- 拦住他 - 没戏了 没戏了
Get him! - He's gone. He's gone.
- 他完全把门守住了 - 不
- He's gotta shut that hole off. - No.
难以置信 连的三分 三分
Unbelievable. Three plays. Three plays.
现在我们多少...4:3？加油
What were we in, 4-3? Come on!
对 小子 你和我 又是我们俩 再来一次
That's right, biggie, me and you. Me and you, biggie, one more time.
来啊
Here we go.
我们得回防了 我们回防
All right, Bobby, cut back. Son, you gotta cut back, you gotta cut back.
- 快点 上 - 死黑鬼
- Come on. Let's go. Back to huddle. - You fat, black piece of crap.
喂 你就这么视而不见？
Hey! Hey! Ref, are you gonna do something about this?
他刚踢了这孩子的头 还骂人
He just kicked my boy in the head and he cussed him!
谢谢
Thank you.
不正当行为 温盖特 后退十五码
Unsportsmanlike conduct, Wingate. Fifteen yards.
- 什么？- 你给我闭嘴 要不再多十五码
- What? - You shut up, you get another 15.
这孩子是我们队的 我们队的
This young man plays for my team. My team!
我要像保护儿子一样保护他
And I will defend him like he's my own son against you...
你们这些红脖子杂种
or any other redneck son of a bitch.
别激动 教练 有我在
Don't worry, coach. I got your back.
好吧
All right.
过来 孩子 过来
Come here, son, come here.
- 试试"缺口"战术 - 缺口？
- Try Gap. - Gap?
缺口
Gap.
好吧 撕开防线 47号突破 其他人继续
All right. Gun rip, 47 Gap. On one, on one.
准备好了？
Ready?
教练不能来保护你了吧 是不是？
Your coach ain't here to protect you now, is he?
预备
Ready!
球队是你的家人 麦克
This team is your family, Michael.
上
Go!
回防 回防 全部拦住
Cut back, out back. Block him, Oher.
继续 继续
He's got a hole! He's got a hole!
天啊
My God.
- 冲啊 麦克 - 小肖
- Get him, Michael. - SJ!
- 追上他 麦克 加油 - 冲 麦克
Get him, Michael. Come on, go! - Run, Michael!
冲 冲 冲
Go  go  go
- 加油 麦克 - 加油 麦克
- Go, Mike! - Go, Michael!
触地得分
Yeah touchdown.
Hey! Hey! Touchdown!
喂 大叔
Yo! Deliverance!
看见74号没？那是我儿子
You see number 74? Well, that's my son.
干得好 大哥
Way to go, bro! Ha-ha-ha.
- 好 现在情况是这样 死球犯规 - 又怎么了？
- Okay, here's what we got. Dead ball foul. - Now what?
- 他有拿球？- 没有
- Was he holding?    - No.
- 哨响后进攻？- 难以置信
- Did he hit after the whistle? - I don't believe so.
那你这是什么意思？
Then what was the ﬂag for?
不知道 过激阻挡
I don't know. Excessive blocking.
开玩笑
You're kidding me.
对不起 教练 听到哨响我就住手了
Sorry, coach. I stopped when I heard the whistle.
你想把他推到哪里去 麦克？
Where were you taking him, Mike?
公车那里 他该回家了
To the bus. It was time for him to go home.
太棒了 麦克•欧尔 太棒了
Attaboy, Michael Oher. Attaboy!
上 干掉他们 十字军们
Go get them! Go get them, Crusaders!
- 哇 - 哇 麦克
- Whoo - Whoo Michael
耶
Yeah.
擦擦头 擦擦头 好 继续
Hey! Hey! Rub the head, rub the head. All right, let's go!
- 哦 - 在那边抢断
- Oh. - Tackle  over there.
上
go!
待在这儿
Stay.
红方41号 红方41号
Ready, 41! Ready, 41!
汤姆•列明 招募办公室 请稍候
Tom Lemming Recruiting, please hold.
萨班教练想让你把每月招募进展快递给他
Coach Saban wants his monthly recruiting updates FedExed.
他真的以为早一天拿到资料
Does he really think getting it one day early
就对路易斯安那州立大学更有利？
is gonna give LSU a leg up?
喂 全明星队伍招满了没有？
Hey, have you filled all the slots in the Army all-star game?
嗯 怎么？
Yeah, why?
这个你肯定有兴趣
You might wanna open one up.
哇
Wow.
我怎么说的来着？
What did I tell you?
我要他 要定他了
I want him. I want him bad.
一二三 大家一起喊  跟我说 一起喊
ALL: Y-E-L-L, everybody yell. Say, everybody yell.
一二三 大家一起喊
Y-E-L-L, everybody yell.
这次踢得不错 柯林斯 干得好
Nice kick this time, Collins. Nice job.
这又是哪一出？
What in the world?
好吧 你们继续训练 记着要碰到脚趾
All right, y'all keep practicing. Remember, point your toes.
一 二 三 一   一 二 三 二   一 二 三 三
One, two, three, one! One, two, three, two! One, two, three, three!
还好吧 孩子？
You gonna buckle up today, son?
干 富尔莫来了 这下我没戏了
Shoot, man, Fulmer's here. Might as well go home.
大家好吧？还不错？
What do you say, fellas? Doing all right? Good to see everybody.
我从诺克斯维尔亲自来看看
Came all the way from Knoxville to see for myself.
你好 教练 我还是从克莱姆森开九小时车过来的呢
Heck, coach, we drove from Clemson, nine hours.
富尔莫教练 很荣幸
Coach Fulmer. It's a real honor.
克顿教练 彼此彼此 我看了你的训练 很不错
My pleasure. I've watched your program. You've done really well.
我想过不了多久 你们的队伍就能晋级了
I don't think there's any question you'll be at the next level soon.
这个 我只能说尽我所能吧
Oh, well, you know, we do what we can with what we've got.
那就是麦克？欧海尔？
Is that...? Is that Michael? Is that O'Hare?
是欧尔 就像海鸟叫 欧尔
It's Oher. Like a paddle in a boat. Oher.
能不能表演一下？也许？
You think we might see some drills, perhaps?
- 我想各位教练也都想看看 - 嗯 没问题 先生
- I think all the coaches would appreciate it. - Oh, yes, sir. You bet.
听着 孩子们 来场对顶
Listen up, fellas! We're gonna do a board drill.
大麦 杰•克里斯 最好对最好 来
Big Mike, Jay Collie, best on best right here.
上啊 加油
Let's go, come on, come on!
听我哨声 小伙子
On the whistle, men.
哇
Wow.
谢谢你 教练
Coach. Thank you.
- 你去哪里 教练？- 回南卡罗来纳
- Where are you off to, coach? - Back to South Carolina.
你告诉麦克•欧尔
You tell Michael Oher,
如果他的成绩合格 克莱姆森大学要他了
if he can qualify with the grades, Clemson wants him.
祝你成功啊 布莱德
Yeah, good luck with that, Brad.
教练 你干得真不错
You've done a great job with this young man.
嗯 一开始他还只是平平...
He was a little raw when we first got him...
不过我训练比较得当
but we've, you know, coached him up a little bit.
你好 妈妈
Hello, Mama.
你知不知道麦克要想拿到甲级奖学金...
Did you know to be eligible for a Division I scholarship...
- 学分积必须达到2.5？- 是吗？
-Michael will need to make a 2.5 GPA? - Really?
他的美国大学检测分数很低
His ACT is low,
这几周在这我也没见到任何好转
I don't see getting any better for these weeks back there.
那他现在学分积多少？
What's his GPA now?
1.76
1.76.
考虑到他的起点 这已经不低了
That's not bad when you consider where he started.
他今年必须全部拿A
Well, he's gonna have to make all A's this year.
我说认真的 而且这可能还不够
I'm serious. And that might not even be enough.
那让他去两年制大专
So he goes to a junior college.
大多数去念大专的小孩 第一年就退学了
Unh-uhn. Most inner-city kids that go to JC drop out in the first year.
那他当专业运动员的机会就泡汤了
And his shot at the pros would go out the window.
专业运动员？你确定有大学会要他？
Pros? Are we even sure he's gonna get college offers?
麦克 我是路易斯安那州大学的尼克•萨班
Michael, Nick Saban from LSU.
希望你有时间能来我们这里看看
Looking forward to you coming down and visiting sometime.
你好 我是南卡大学的卢•霍兹 我想...
Greetings, I'm Lou Holtz from South Carolina. I'm call...
我们很欢迎麦克来诺克斯维尔看看
We are very interested in having Michael over to Knoxville for a visit.
田纳西大学的菲尔•富尔莫？
Phil Fulmer, Tennessee.
还有二十多个电话
There's 20 more of them on there.
这边还有五十份材料
And these things right here, 50 of them.
- 有没有密西西比大学的？- 没有
- Any of those from Ole Miss? - No.
没有 除非他们新雇佣一个教练才会再招募
They're not gonna start recruiting till they hire another coach.
不过麦克成绩不合格的话 这些都白说
Doesn't make any difference unless Michael makes his grades. Ahem.
那我们怎么办？
What are we gonna do?
我看到你应聘温盖特中学的职位
I understand you applied for a teaching position at Wingate.
他们觉得我宗教方面不合要求
I wasn't religious enough for them.
我是属神的 图伊太太 不过我还是有些...困惑
I'm a spiritual person, Mrs. Tuohy, but I have certain, shall we say, doubts.
我很欣赏你的坦诚 苏小姐
Well, I appreciate your honesty, Miss Sue.
麦克是什么情况？
What's the situation with Michael?
- 他需要提高成绩 - 这是很明显的
- He needs to do better in school. - Obviously.
但是为什么这么着急？
But why the big push?
他要是能提高成绩就能申请到橄榄球奖学金
Well, he's in line for a football scholarship if he gets his grades up.
- 他考虑过密西西比大学吗？- 我也希望
- Is he considering Ole Miss? - Better be.
我想跟他合作
I'd love to work with him.
那你什么时候可以开始？
Well  when would you like to start?
图伊女士 我...想先跟你说一件事
Mrs. Tuohy, um, there's something you should know about me.
我通常不告诉别人...
I don't usually tell many people...
不过我觉得你雇佣我之前应该知晓
but it's something I feel you should be aware of before you hire me.
什么事？
What is it?
我是民主党人
I'm a Democrat.
好的
Okay.
- 我不明白 - 只是还不明白
- I don't understand it. - Yet.
你现在还不明白而已
You don't understand it yet.
你头有多大 麦克？
How big is your head, Michael?
很大
Big.
里面有什么？
And what's in there?
- 大脑 - 大脑
- A brain. - A brain.
装满了知识
It's full of knowledge.
像是装满了地图的柜子 是通向智慧的捷径
Like a file cabinet with maps, and shortcuts for figuring things out.
你会成功的 麦克•欧尔
You'll get there, Michael Oher,
因为我会帮助你用好那些地图...
because I'm here to help you use those maps...
让你到达成功彼岸 就像...
and reach your destination, like...
萨卡加韦帮助路易士和克拉克那样
Sacagawea led Lewis and Clark.
萨卡加韦？
Sacagawea?
后面会讲到 虽然历史书上写的是错误的
We'll get to that. And the history books have it wrong.
你只要知道 我会助你成功
All you need to know is I'll get you there.
你相信我吗？
Do you believe me?
你信任我吗 麦克？
You trust me, Michael?
我信任你 苏小姐
Yes, Miss Sue.
再试试看
Try it again.
下一道题是什么？读给我听 上面写的什么？
What's the next one? Read that to me. Okay, what does it say?
首先我们要找到常量 那么常量在哪里？
First we have to find the constant. Now, where is the constant?
很好 看见没？
Good. See?
我们居然在认识民主党人之前 有了个黑人儿子
Who'd have thought we'd have a black son before we knew a Democrat?
- 门铃响了 - 我来开门
- Doorbell!     - I got it, guys.
你好 教练 请进 肖恩•图伊
Coach, how are you? Come in. Sean Tuohy.
你好 肖恩 很高兴见到你 很高兴认识你
Sean, Nice to see you. Nice to meet you.
我的荣幸
My pleasure.
很感谢能让我来你们家
I appreciate the opportunity to come in your home.
- 这是我女儿 柯林斯 - 见到你很高兴
- This is my daughter, Collins. - Pleasure to meet you.
- 你一定是莉•安妮了 - 没错 萨班教练
- And you must be Leigh Anne. - That would be me, Coach Saban.
- 幸会 - 彼此彼此
- Nice to meet you. - You too.
请叫我尼克 房子真漂亮
Just call me Nick. This is an incredible home.
那些温莎帐幔手感很好
The Windsor valances are a nice touch.
谢谢 看来您很有品位
Well, thank you. You obviously have excellent taste.
我们对好东西一向很欣赏
Well, we appreciate quality...
而且一见到就能认出来
and recognize it when we see it.
- 麦克 过来跟萨班教练打声招呼 - 嗨 麦克
- Michael, why don't you come in and say hello to coach Saban? - Hi, Michael.
- 我是尼克•萨班 见到你很高兴 - 我也是
- Nick Saban. Nice to meet you. - Nice to meet you.
- 你一定是小肖了 - 没错
And you must be SJ. - That's me.
麦克 你和尼克去客厅谈吧？
Michael, why don't you and Nick go into the living room and talk?
小肖可以来吗？
Can SJ come?
- 没问题 你们两个我都要了 - 好吧
- Absolutely. We'll recruit the both of you. - All right.
他真帅
I find him extremely handsome.
我还没走呢 莉•安妮
Yeah, I'm right here, Leigh Anne.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
麦克 我们希望你去路易斯安那州大学走走
So, Michael, we would love to get you down to LSU for a visit.
现在有个绝好机会
We've got a great thing going right now.
你有机会成为一个成功的人 成功的学生...
You have an opportunity to be successful as a person, as a student...
同时也有机会代表路大参加下一届全国冠军赛
and an opportunity to be a part of the next national championship team at LSU.
怎么样？考虑考虑？
So, what do you say? Would you like to commit to a visit?
- 我能问个问题吗？- 说
- Can I ask a question? - Sure.
我大哥跟我很亲近 所以...
My brother and I are very close, and so...
我怕他去了你那里 我就见不到他了
I'm very afraid that if he goes off to school, I might not get to see him.
- 所以... - 你说
- So... - Go on.
我想问我有多少机会可以接触他？
I guess I was just wondering how much access I'd have to him.
这个 小肖 完全没有障碍
Well, SJ, you would have total access to Michael.
而且更棒的是 他第一次去老虎体育馆比赛的时候...
But better than that, in his first game in Tiger Stadium...
你还可以带队出场
we would like for you to lead the team out of the tunnel.
- 你看怎样？- 听起来不错
- What do you think about that? - Sounds good.
请进
Come on in.
你好 我是卢•霍尔兹 南卡大学
Greetings. I'm Lou Holtz from the University of South Carolina.
我是莉•安妮•图伊 幸会 请进 麦克？
Leigh Anne Tuohy. Nice to meet you. Come on in. Michael?
我是莉•安妮•图伊 幸会 麦克
Leigh Anne Tuohy. Nice to meet you. Michael?
你好 我是阿肯色大学的休士顿•纳特
Houston Nutt, University of Arkansas.
我是莉•安妮•图伊 幸会
Leigh Anne Tuohy. Nice to meet you.
- 密西西比大学的杯子 嗯？- 麦克？
- Ole Miss cup, huh?       - Michael?
加油 你会的
Oh, come on. You know this.
这是逻辑问题
It's logical.
我保证 加入南卡大学...
I guarantee, you come to University of South Carolina...
将是你一生无悔的选择
it'll be the smartest decision you've ever made.
我们需要你 而且另一方面 你也需要我们 麦克
We want you, we need you, but the other thing is, Mike, you need us.
啊
Ow
诺克斯维尔很适合生活 而且...
Knoxville is a tremendous place to live and...
我知道那里有狮子 老虎和熊
I know there's Lions, there's Tigers, there's Bears.
那里有世上唯一的一只剃刀鲸
Hey, there's only one Razorback in the world.
而且呢 你穿斗鸡红战袍一定好看
And not only that, you will look great in Gamecock red.
我有什么好处？
What's in it for me?
小肖 我可以给你一顶雄鹰帽 全家每人一顶
SJ, I'm gonna get you a hog hat and the whole family a hog hat.
你只能做到这些？
Are you telling me that's the best you can do?
小肖 你让我想起小时候的我
SJ, you remind me of me as a boy.
教练 帮人就是帮己
Coach, help me help you.
我可以给一个斗鸡头饰 用真的羽毛噢
I can give you a Gamecock headdress, and with real feathers.
- 能给我什么好处 菲尔？- 这事我想了很久...
- What do you got for me, Phil? - I've been thinking a lot about that...
最特别不过的...
and one of the things I think would be special...
就是你和我在第一场比赛手挽手走进联合体育馆
is we'll walk arm-in-arm to the center of Neyland Stadium in the first ball game...
我们还可以一起扔硬币 怎么样?
and do the coin toss together. How's that sound?
富尔莫教练 和你做生意很荣幸
Coach Fulmer, it's a pleasure doing business with you.
彼此彼此 小家伙
My pleasure, CJ. You bet you, buddy.
（十字军队将参加私立学校冠军赛）
祝贺你得到这份工作
Congratulations on getting hired.
谢谢你 女士 密西西比大学是我梦想的学校
Thank you, ma'am. Ole Miss is my dream job.
你来的有点晚了 不过还好有我们在
You're coming a little late to the party and we're diehard Rebels...
我给你交个底吧 如何？
so I'm gonna pretty much give you a road map. All right?
- 明白 - 路易斯安那州大学没戏了
- Got it.       - LSU is out.
大家都知道萨班要去联盟执教了...
Everybody knows Saban's going to the NFL.
我不想点名 不过前两次麦克去某些大学参观的时候...
Don't wanna name names, but on Michael's first two trips...
- 有人带他去脱衣舞吧 - 太可怕了
- somebody took him to a titty bar. - Terrible.
可不是吗 他做了一周的噩梦
Tell me about it. He had nightmares for weeks.
所以去密西西比大学参观的时候 给他上意大利菜
So when he visits, I want you to feed him Italian.
他喜欢阿尔弗雷多白脱奶油面 还有 带他去看电影
He likes fettuccine Alfredo. And take him to a movie.
不过不要电锯杀人狂那种
Not Chainsaw Massacre.
他会闭上眼不看 还有 十点前让他上床 明白？
because he'll just cover his eyes. Then get him in bed by 10. Got it?
- 是的 女士 - 好吧
- Yes, ma'am. - All right.
- 那田纳西呢？- 嗯
- What about Tennessee?     - Mm.
虽然我不喜欢 但他们仍有机会
Breaks my heart, but they're still in the hunt.
富尔莫给了小肖很诱人的条件
Ahem. Fulmer made SJ a sweet deal.
听说这孩子很能折腾
I hear that kid can really pepper the gumbo.
有其父必有其子 准备好了？
He's his daddy's boy. You ready?
- 开始吧 - 好吧
- Let's do it. - All right.
麦克 你喜欢烧烤吗？这么说吧
Mike, do you love barbecue? I tell you what, Mike.
就算是去加油站 你都能吃到以前吃不到的美味烧烤
You can go to a gas station and get the best barbecue you ever got.
那地方棒极了
It's a wonderful place to live.
炸鱼 还有各种美食...
Fried catfish, all the good food that we love to eat...
当然这对我们橄榄球运动员是不好的 你得悠着点 麦克
and that's not good for us, football players. you can have it there, Mike, I promise you.
至于你 小肖 我可以答应你的是
And for you, SJ, this is what I can do.
在密西西比大学 球场旁边有一条路
At Ole Miss, we have The Grove by the stadium.
每次我们会在数千人的注目下走过那里
We walk it before every game in front of thousands of people.
这是一个神圣的仪式 我走在前面
It's a sacred ritual. And I'm in front.
见惯了
Seen it a thousand times.
有走在前面过吗？明年 我和你来带队
Ever seen it from the front of the line? Next year, you and me, leading the team.
田纳西让我领队进场 还让我扔硬币
Tennessee offered to let me run on the field and flip the coin.
我可以给你场内通行证
I'll throw in a sideline pass.
你决定了吗 麦克？
Have you decided yet, Michael?
还没 苏小姐
No, Miss Sue.
但你喜欢田纳西？
But you like Tennessee?
学校不错
Yeah. That's a good school.
虽然学术水准不如密西西比大学...
Not at the academic level of Ole Miss...
不过他们的科学院很不错
but they have a outstanding Science Department.
你知道他们以什么著名吗？
You know what they're famous for?
他们跟FBI合作...
They work with the FBI...
他们专门研究被肢解的尸体
to study the effects of soil on decomposing body parts.
什么意思？
What's that mean?
警方找到尸体之后会想知道死了多久
Well, when they find a body, the police wanna know how long it's been dead.
然后田纳西大学的人就会来帮忙
So the fine folks at Tennessee help them out.
他们有很多人体部件
Oh, they have lots of body parts.
胳膊啦 腿啦 手啦...
Arms and legs and hands...
从医院和医学院拿来的
from hospitals and medical schools.
你知道他们放在哪里吗？
And do you know where they store them?
就在球场下面
Right underneath the football field.
所以获胜的时候呢 会有十万粉丝为你庆贺呢...
So while it's fine and dandy to have 100,000 fans cheering for you...
那些在草皮下面埋着的尸体你可要小心了
the bodies you should be worried about are the ones right under the turf.
可能会钻出草皮抓住你
Set to poke up through the ground and grab you.
当然了 你自己决定去哪里
Well, it's your decision where you wanna play ball.
别受我影响
Don't let me influence you.
其他老师都很合作 我不知道你这里什么问题
All the other teachers are on board. I don't know what your problem is.
抱歉 我不能给学生他不应得的分数
I'm sorry. I will not give a student a grade he or she doesn't deserve.
麦克需要一个B
Well, Michael needs a B.
怎么样才算是应得的？
What does he have to do to deserve that?
现在麦克的水准是D+到C-
Right now Michael's doing C-minus, D-plus work.
他最好在写作上下功夫 因为到年底的时候
His best chance at improvement is the written essay at the end of the year.
写作能占三分之一的比重
It counts for a third of the grade.
好吧 服了你了
Well, that's it. We're sunk.
不如写关于《远大前程》的？
Why don't you write about Great Expectations?
你很像皮普
You're a lot like Pip.
他也很穷 也是个孤儿 后来有人领养他了
I mean, he was poor. He was an orphan and someone kind of found him.
你应该比较有同感
You should be able to relate to that.
好吧 我们再找一找
Fine. We'll go through the reading list.
但你一定得选一篇 麦克
But you're gonna have to pick one, Michael.
《卖花女》
Pygmalion.
《双城记》
A Tale of Two Cities.
"轻骑兵的冲锋"
"The Charge of the Light Brigade."
"伤亡过半 伤亡过半 半只队伍向前冲"
"Half a league, half a league Half a league onward"
我很喜欢这个
I love that one.
他很喜欢这个
He loves it.
不如你来搞 我看篮球？
Why don't you do this? And I'll watch basketball.
好吧
Okay.
"一齐杀进死亡谷 六百马背英雄"
"All in the valley of Death Rode the six hundred."
路大的体育馆就因为这个故事 起名叫做"死亡谷"
They named LSU's stadium Death Valley because of this story.
艾尔弗雷德•坦尼森勋爵写的...
Alfred, Lord Tennyson...
在密西西比大学 他们引用了它
was writing about LSU-Ole Miss.
- 不会吧？- 没错
- You're kidding. - No.
- 这是个很好的故事 - 是一首诗
- It's a great story. - It's a poem!
"向前 轻骑旅 "
"Forward, the Light Brigade!"
这就好比进攻方
That's like the offense.
一个战士喊 "向炮火进攻"
"Charge for the guns," he said:
这就好比球门区
It's the end zone.
"一齐杀进死亡谷 六百马背英雄"
"Into the valley of Death Rode the six hundred."
"向前 轻骑旅 有谁还能面带惶恐？"
"Forward, the Light Brigade!" Was there a man dismay'd?"
这呼喊只是脱口而出 其中的含义他还不懂"
"Not tho' the soldier knew Someone had blunder'd"
有人犯错误了？
Someone made a mistake?
没错 带队人
Yeah. Their leader.
教练
Their coach.
但既然知道会失败 为什么还要向前冲？
But why would they go ahead if they knew he messed up?
"尽管无人回应"
"Theirs not to make reply"
"尽管心里朦胧 可是个个视死如归 无比奋勇"
"Theirs not to reason why Theirs but to do and die"
一齐杀进死亡谷 六百马背英雄"
"Into the valley of Death Rode the six hundred."
他们全都会死 对吧？
They're all gonna die, aren't they?
是的
Yeah.
真的很凄凉
That's really, really sad.
我想你有东西写了 麦克
I think you just found something to write about, Michael.
勇气是很难说清楚的东西
Courage is a hard thing to figure.
也许你的勇气只是愚勇...
You can have courage based on a dumb idea or a mistake...
但你不该质问大人...
but you're not supposed to question adults...
不管是教练还是老师 因为规矩是他们定的
or your coach or your teacher because they make the rules.
也许他们什么都知道 也许不是
Maybe they know best, but maybe they don't.
这都要看你是谁 你来自哪里
It all depends on who you are, where you come from.
那六百个勇士 难道没有一人想过要放弃
Didn't at least one of the 600 guys think about giving up...
向敌方投降？
and joining with the other side?
我是说 死亡谷是个很壮烈的地方
I mean, valley of Death, that's pretty salty stuff.
所以勇气这东西其实也很微妙
That's why courage is tricky.
你是不是总应该服从别人的指令？
Should you always do what others tell you to do?
有时候也许你根本都不知道为什么要这么做
Sometimes you might not even know why you're doing something.
傻子也可以有勇气
I mean, any fool can have courage.
但荣誉才是你做人做事真正的动力
But honor, that's the real reason you either do something or you don't.
荣誉代表了你是谁 你想成为谁
It's who you are and maybe who you want to be.
如果你为了有意义的事而死...
If you die trying for something important...
那你就既有勇气也有了荣誉 这样很好
then you have both honor and courage, and that's pretty good.
我想作者就是要表达这个意思
I think that's what the writer was saying.
人需要争取荣誉 并希望被赞美有勇气
That you should hope for courage and try for honor.
也许还要祈祷给他下指令的人也能做到这样
And maybe even pray that the people telling you what to do have some too.
凯文•林
Kevin Lin.
- 干得好  - 借过 借过 借过
- Good job. - Excuse me. Excuse me. Excuse me.
马修•尼科尔斯
Matthew Nichols.
- 2.52 - 嗯？
-2.52. - Hmm?
麦克最终的学分积 刚从保尔的电脑上拿到的
Michael's final GPA. Got it off of Paul's computer.
吉米•诺斯
Jimmy North
他成功了 肖恩 成功了
He did it, Sean. He did it.
宝贝 你黑了校长的电脑？
Wait a minute. You broke into the principal's computer?
嗯？
Hmm?
麦克•欧尔
Michael Oher.
你哪里找的麦克小时候的照片？
Where in the world did you find a baby picture of Michael?
从网上广告里截下来的
Scanned it off an Internet ad for a toddler boutique.
- 恭喜你 麦克 - 谢谢
- Congratulations, Michael. - Thank you.
恭喜你 麦克
Michael, up top!
干得好 大哥
Way to go, bro.
行了 够了 年轻人
All right, that's enough.
你该给我一个像样的拥抱
Young man, I think I need a proper hug.
好 你会住在迪顿大厦 在哪里？
You're gonna be staying in Deaton Hall. Where is it?
109 这里
It's 109. It's right there.
然后吃饭 在强生食堂这里
You'll be on the meal plan so you'll be eating over here in Johnson Commons.
强生食堂有自助冰淇淋
Johnson Commons, all-you-can-eat self-serve ice cream.
随便吃？
As much as you want?
对 妈妈大一的时候就是这么长了十磅的
That's how Mama put on her freshman 10.
少来
Stop it.
喂？
Hello?
我是图伊太太
This is Mrs. Tuohy.
他就问你几个问题 麦克 没什么可隐瞒的
They just wanna ask you a couple questions, Michael. You have nothing to hide.
图伊太太？欧尔先生？我叫乔思林•葛兰杰
Mrs. Tuohy? Mr. Oher? My name is Jocelyn Granger.
我是全国大学生体育协会的执法助理主任
I'm the Assistant Director of Enforcement for the NCAA.
请叫我 莉•安妮
Please, call me Leigh Anne.
我们开始吧？
So let's do this, shall we?
图伊太太 如果您不介意 我想和麦克单独谈谈
If you wouldn't mind, I'd prefer to speak with Michael alone.
那要多久？
And how long is that gonna take?
一会儿
A While.
那好吧
It's all right. It's okay.
去吧
Go on.
麦克
Michael.
麦克 我在大厅等你
Michael. I'll be waiting for you in the lobby.
好吗？
All right?
不知道 肖恩
I don't know, Sean.
我就是有点不好的预感
Just have a bad feeling about this one.
这女人有点咄咄逼人...等下
This woman is tough, tough, tough, tough, tough. Hold on.
嘿
Hey.
客户要什么？
The client wants what?
你知不知道克顿教练接受了密西西比大学的教职？
Were you aware that Coach Cotton was accepting a job at Ole Miss?
不知道
No.
而且是在你跟他们签合约之后？
And that this job offer came after you signed with them?
你的法定监护人肖恩•图伊 在密西西比大学读过书
Sean Tuohy, your legal guardian, went to Ole Miss.
他打篮球
He played basketball.
图伊太太也在密西西比大学读的书
And Mrs. Tuohy went to Ole Miss as well.
她是个啦啦队员
She was a cheerleader.
我是不是可以说 密西西比大学是他们最喜欢的学校？
Is it safe to say that Ole Miss is their favorite school?
他们喜欢别的大学吗？比如田纳西大学？
Do they like any other universities? What about, say, Tennessee?
不 他们忍受不了田纳西
No, they can't stand Tennessee.
- 你的家庭教师 - 苏小姐
- And your tutor. - Miss Sue?
苏小姐 她也是密西西比大学毕业的
Miss Sue. Miss Sue is an Ole Miss grad too.
苏小姐有没有劝说你去密西西比大学？
Miss Sue ever try to persuade you to attend Ole Miss?
你知不知道图伊一家经常给密西西比大学捐款？
Did you know that the Tuohys make generous donations to Ole Miss?
甚至苏小姐也有捐款？
That even Miss Sue makes donations?
图伊家还在牛津有座公寓...
That the Tuohys, they have a condo in Oxford...
这样他们可以很方便的观看比赛
so they can attend as many athletic events as possible.
事实上呢 我们把肖恩和莉•安妮•图伊...
That in fact, both Sean and Leigh Anne Tuohy...
成为"拥护者"
are by our definition boosters.
欧尔先生
Mr. Oher.
欧尔先生？
你明不明白？知道我为什么找你吗？
Do you understand? Do you know why I'm here?
想...调查？
To investigate?
对 调查
Yes. To investigate.
我想调查你不寻常的...处境
I'm here to investigate your odd...predicament.
你觉得你的处境奇怪吗？
Do you find it odd, your predicament?
麦克
Michael.
不知道
I don't know.
- 我...可以走了吗？- 不行
- Can I...? Can I leave now? - No, you can't.
你想要什么 女士？
What do you want, ma'am?
- 我要事实 告诉我真相 - 我没撒谎
- I want the facts. I need the truth. - I didn't lie.
- 我想知道你自己的想法 - 想什么？
- I wanna know what you think about this. - Think about what?
大学生体协生怕此例一开...
The NCAA fears that with your recruitment...
后患无穷...
a door might be opened...
南方许多学校的支持者...
that boosters from schools in the South...
就会通过各种手段成为年轻运动员的监护人...
will become legal guardians of young athletes without means...
从而向他们的母校输送人才
and funnel them to their alma maters.
我没说我相信 也没说不信
I'm not saying I believe it. I'm not saying I don't.
但很多人会说 图伊一家
But there are many people involved in this case who would argue that the Tuohys...
- 他们收留了你 给你买衣服 食物 - 不
- they took you in, they clothed you... - No.
- 他们让你上私立学校 - 不
- they fed you, they paid for your private education. - No.
- 他们给你买车 给你请家庭教师... - 不 不
- They bought you a car, paid for a tutor... - No. No.
最终都是为了你能为密西西比大学效力
all as part of a plan to ensure that you play football for the University of Mississippi.
麦克 这事还没完呢
Michael? We're not finished.
没货 我三个月前就说过
The toile's not available, like I told you months ago.
为什么不用帆布呢？那款很好看...
So why don't we go with the ticking? The low nap. It's a beautiful...
我回头再打给你 再见 麦克 怎么了？
I'll call you back. Bye. Michael. So, what happened?
- 你为什么这么做？- 什么？
- Why'd you do it? - What?
你一直想让我去密西西比大学
All along you wanted me to go to Ole Miss.
当然 我们都爱密西西比大学
Well, of course I did. We love Ole Miss.
- 你为什么要为我做这些事？- 什么？
- Why'd you do this for me? - What?
所有这一切 你是为了自己 还是为我？
Everything. Was it for you or was it for me'?
是不是这样 我就可以去你想让我去的学校？
Was it so I would go to school where you wanted?
是不是这样 我就可以走你安排的路？
Was it so I would do what you wanted?
- 麦克 不... - 她就是这么认为的
- Michael, no, I... - That's what she thinks.
她说得对吗？
Is she right?
麦克 亲爱的 听我说好吗？
Michael, honey, I need for you to just listen to me.
你敢骗我
Don't you dare lie to me.
我不傻
I'm not stupid.
麦克？麦克 你当然不傻 麦克 别这样
Michael? Michael, of course you're not stupid, Michael. Come on.
我应该跟着他的
I should've followed him.
你不可能知道他会消失
You had no way of knowing he'd disappear.
他说的对吗？
Was he right?
关于我们的想法？
What he said about us?
莉•安妮 理智一点
Leigh Anne, be reasonable.
我们给了一个衣衫褴褛的孩子衣服穿 我们给了他一张床
We gave clothes to a boy who had one pair of shorts and we gave him a bed.
去他妈的大学生体协 再给我一次机会 我还会这么做
To hell with the NCAA. I would do it again tomorrow.
那其他那些呢？
What about all the rest of it?
我们做了那么多事 让他能拿到奖学金？
All the stuff we did to make sure that he got a scholarship.
密西西比大学的奖学金
A scholarship to Ole Miss.
他可以自己选择的 他清楚这一点
He could go anywhere he wanted. He knew that.
是吗？你问过他吗？我确定我从来没问过
Oh, did he? Did you ask him? Because I sure as hell know I never did.
过来
Hey. Come here.
嗯
Yeah.
我是个好人吗？
Am I a good person?
不开玩笑
Not a joke.
客观一点
Not rhetorical.
你是我认识的最好的人
You are the best person that I know.
你做的一切都是为了别人
Everything you do, you do for others.
我为什么要这样？
And why is that?
我也不知道
I have not a clue.
但显然你能获得一种变态的满足感
But you obviously get some sort of sick satisfaction out of it.
- 肖恩 - 嗯？
- Sean. - Yeah?
要是他再也不回来呢？
What if he never comes back?
我操
Oh. Heh. Whoo!
大麦？嘿 快过来
Big Mike. Hey, get your ass on in here, man.
- 我找我妈妈 - 你妈妈？
- I'm looking for my mama. - Your mama?
我好像见过她
Yeah  I seen Dee Dee around.
其实呢...
As a matter of fact...
哦对 她最近的确会来买一些好货
Oh, yeah, she usually stop by for a taste around this time.
不如你先进来
Look, I tell you what, why don't you just come on inside?
我给你一瓶好酒 哥几个慢慢喝 等她过来
I'm gonna get you a 40, we gonna chop it up like real folk. Just until she get here.
来吧 兄弟 没人咬你
Come on, now. Ain't nobody gonna bite you, baby.
嗨 大麦 过来坐
HeY Hey, Big Mike, go on down there in the living room, man. Have a seat.
让这婊子呆在这
Liven this bitch up in here  y'all.
宝贝 给我从冰箱里拿些啤酒来
Give me a couple of 40s out that refrigerator.
- 坐下 兄弟 - 大麦
- Sit down, man. - Big Mike, boy.
真高兴见到你
Damn, sure good to see you.
是啊 你看起来不错 身体也很好
Yeah, you looking good too. You looking fit.
听说你在打球
I heard you playing a little ball.
但你知道那种有钱人玩的球 可不像公立学校联赛
Y'all know that old rich-kid football ain't got nothing on that public-school league.
这里黑鬼们会在袜子里藏刀
Niggas packing knives in they socks.
我自己也玩的
Hey. I played a little ball myself.
- 记得吗 过去？- 听说过
- Back in the day. You knew that, right? - Yeah, I heard.
四分卫 在马丁•路德•金学校
Little quarterback. Up there at MLK. Yeah.
谢谢 宝贝 你呢 戴夫？
Thank you, baby. What about you, David?
你还在大专打球？
You still playing ball over at JC?
不了 没呢 哥们 戴夫已经不是学生了
Naw, br... No, man. David ain't with that no more.
他现在跟我混
He with me now.
其实呢 我也给你留了个位子
As a matter of fact, look, I can open up a spot for you too.
上学太累了 那些人老是指手画脚
I got tired of going to class. People always trying to tell me what to do.
听我说 戴夫... 开大声点 像那个婊子一样
Well, in that case, then, look here, turn that up right there, little-bitty bitch!
- 哈哈哈 - 贱货
- Ha-ha-ha. - Bitty bitch!
别耍戴夫了 兄弟
Hey, man. I'm just messing with D, man.
听说你住在城那边
Ahh. I heard you staying on the other side of town.
没错 你妈也这么说 说你有个新妈妈了 是吗？
Yeah, that what Dee Dee said. Said you got you a new mama now. Yeah, man.
- 是的 - 是个好女人 嗯 好女人
- Hell, yeah. - She fine too. Yeah, she fine. Mm-mm. Ooh!
她还有小孩吗？
Hey, she got any other kids?
有女儿吗？
She got a daughter?
你上过了吗？
You tap that?
哇 你上过了 赞
Yeah. Yeah, you tapped that, didn't you? Yeah.
大麦
Big Mike!
大麦上了白女人 还装傻
ALTON: Big Mike clone got a little piece, y'all! He can't stand hisself now.
嗨 大...
Hey, Big...
你应该好好享受 哥们
He done... He done lost his mind.
你去哪里？
Hey, where you going?
去家门口等我妈妈
I'm gonna just go wait for Mama at the apartment.
先别走 哥们
Hey, man. Just go on heading on.
来 坐下 我就是想多了解一些你的漂亮白妹妹
Sit down. I'm just trying to find out a little bit about your fine white sister.
我喜欢这种乱伦情节
Because I likes me some of that mommy-daughter action.
闭嘴
Shut up.
闭嘴？
Shut up?
你他妈的让谁闭嘴？
Who in the hell is you telling to shut up?
看我不把你的大屁股打爆...
I will bust a cap in your fat ass...
然后开车往东去拜访你的新妈妈...
and then drive east to pay a visit to your cracker-ass mama...
还有她可爱的小女儿
and her sweet little daughter.
我的孩子
My baby
你个禽兽 滚出去
You monster. Get out
妈妈
Mama!
他走了 雪花
He gone, snowflake.
麦克来过？
Michael was here?
对 但你转告他 我会去找他的 要不就是他来找我
Yeah, but you tell him I'll be seeing him around. Oh, he gonna get his.
那么麦克来过？
So Michael was here?
昨晚来过 打了我 跑了
Last night. Gonna come by here and sneak me then run off.
对 告诉他 晚上睡觉小心点
Yeah. Tell him to sleep with one eye open.
听到了吗 贱人？
You hear me, bitch?
不 你给我听着 贱货
No, you hear me, bitch.
你威胁我儿子 还威胁我
You threaten my son, you threaten me.
你要够胆去城里 你会后悔的
You so much as cross into downtown, you will be sorry.
我和地区检察官在同一个祈祷团
I'm in a prayer group with the DA...
我还是全国步枪射击运动协会的成员
...I'm a member of the NRA,
我的枪随时上膛
and I'm always packing.
你带着什么枪 点22？还是周六特别枪？
What you got in there, a .22? Or a Saturday Night Special?
它每天都能射得很准
Mm-hm. And it shoots just fine all the other days too.
- 麦克？- 妈妈？
- Michael? - Mama?
警察会不会来抓我？
You think the police are gonna come and get me?
赫特村那帮人最怕的...
I imagine the last thing they want in Hurt Village...
就是旁边有警察晃悠
is a bunch of cops snooping around.
我本不该问你 不过你为什么离开了那里 麦克？
I swore I would never ask this, but how did you get out of there, Michael?
我小时候 有什么可怕的事情...
When I was little and something awful was happening...
妈妈都会让我闭上眼睛
my mama would tell me to close my eyes.
她一直不想让我看见她吸毒的样子 或其他不好的事情
She was trying to keep me from seeing her do drugs or other bad things.
一旦她吸完了 或是坏事过去了...
And when she was finished or the bad things were over...
她就会说 "我数到三 你就可以睁眼"
she'd say, "Now when I count to three, you open your eyes."
"过去的就过去了 世界又安静了 一切都很好"
"The past is gone, the world is a good place, and it's all gonna be okay."
你会闭上眼睛
You closed your eyes.
知道吗 我找你的路上...
You know, when I was driving all over kingdom come looking for you...
一直在想一件事
I kept thinking about one thing.
小牛费迪南
Ferdinand the Bull.
我知道我早就该问你 麦克
I know I should've asked you this a long time ago, Michael.
你想打橄榄球吗？
But do you even wanna play football?
我是说 你到底喜欢吗？
I mean, do you even like it?
我玩的不错
I'm pretty good at it.
是啊 没错
Yeah  you are.
肖恩和我谈过...
Sean and I have been talking and...
麦克 如果要接受橄榄球奖学金...
Michael, if you're gonna accept a football scholarship...
我们觉得你还是该选择田纳西
we think it should be to Tennessee.
我保证 每场比赛都会到场为你加油
And I promise that I will be at every game, cheering for you.
- 每场？- 每场
- Every game? - Every game.
但我不喜欢那屎黄色
But I will not wear that gaudy orange. I will not.
就是不喜欢 我不会穿那衣服
It is not in my color wheel and I'm not gonna wear it.
那你想让我去田纳西？
So you want me to go to Tennessee?
我想让你自己选择
I want you to do whatever you want.
这是你的生活 你自己做主
It is your decision, Michael. It's your life.
要是我不想打球呢？
What if I wanted to flip burgers?
这是你的生活 你自己做主
It's your decision. It's your life.
好吧
Okay.
好什么？
Okay, what?
很抱歉我前天就那么走开
I'm sorry I left the other day.
- 因为你很难过 - 你问了很多问题
- You were pretty upset. - You asked a lot of questions.
- 我只是想搞个明白 - 但你一直在问...
- I'm just trying to get to the bottom of this. - But all the questions you asked...
为什么我周围的人都想让我去密西西比大学
were about why everybody else wanted me to go to Ole Miss.
没错
Okay.
但你怎么不问我为什么选择她
Not once did you ask why did I wanna go there.
好吧
All right.
那好 麦克 你为什么选择了密西西比大学？
Fine, Michael. Why do you wanna go to Ole Miss?
因为我家里人都在那里读过书
Because it's where my family goes to school.
他们都在那里上学
It's where they've always gone to school.
大学生活会很不一样的 麦克
College will be a different experience for you, Michael.
别闹了 小肖
SJ, stop it.
- 花花世界 - 尽情玩吧
- There's gonna be lots of distractions. - Have fun.
你同屋可能是宅男 通宵打电动...
Always gonna be some nimrod in the dorm who wants to play video games all night...
或者上网泡妞
or fool around on the Internet.
尽情玩吧
Just have fun.
你将会花很多时间训练 所以...
You'll be spending a lot of time at practice...
所以你必须抓紧剩下的时间学习 好吗？
which means you'll have to be very dedicated to your studies, all right?
- 小肖 如果你不马上停下来 过来 - 放松点 妈妈
- SJ, if you don't stop right now, Come here. - Relax, Mama.
我刚从图书馆回来 我定了一学期的座位
I just got back from the library. I reserved a private cubicle for the semester.
这是你的课表 还有我们的自习计划
Here's your class schedule and our study-hall hours.
没事的话 我先去我的公寓了
Now, if y'all don't mind, I'm gonna go move into my new apartment.
- 谢谢你 苏小姐 - 谢谢你 苏小姐
- Thank you, Miss Sue. - Thank you, Miss Sue.
好好好
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
看看这上面都有什么课 大学写作 很好
Let's see what you got here. College Writing, good.
心理学 数学试验...
Psychology, Math Lab...
很不错 只是... 不知道为什么
which is gonna be good. Just... Well, you know Why.
很多很好的课
A lot of good classes.
- 你会过得很开心 - 小肖
- You gonna have a lot of fun. - SJ!
麦克•欧尔 你给我听着
Michael Oher, you listen to me, all right?
你可以享受生活 不过你要是把哪个女生肚子搞大了...
I want you to enjoy yourself, but if you get a girl pregnant out of wedlock...
我立刻就会杀到牛津来 砍掉你的小鸡鸡
I will crawl in the car, drive up here to Oxford, and I will cut off your penis.
她说真的
She means it.
- 遵命 女士 - 好吧
- Yes, ma'am. - All right.
时间不早了 我们该走了...
Well, the 78's gonna be a parking lot so we should get going...
每个人说再见 好吗？来
I want everyone to say their goodbyes, all right? Here.
她为什么老这样？
Why does she always do that?
她是一颗洋葱 麦克 你得一层层剥开
She's an onion, Michael. You have to peel her back a layer at a time.
等我一下
Be right back.
干嘛？
What?
干嘛 麦克？
What, Michael?
我想要一个像样的拥抱
I need a proper hug.
我前天听说了一个男孩的故事
I read a story the other day about a boy from the projects.
（本地少年被枪杀）
没有父亲 几进几出孤儿院
No daddy, in and out of foster care.
他在赫特村的黑帮械斗中被杀
He'd been killed in a gang fight at Hurt Village.
文章最后一段提到了他超人的运动天赋...
In the last paragraph, they talked about his superb athletic skills...
还说如果他没有退学...
and how different his life might've been...
生活将完全不同
if he hadn't fallen behind and dropped out of school.
他死那天才21岁
He was 21 years old the day he died.
正好是他的生日
It was his birthday.
他只是碰巧被杀
That could have been anyone.
麦克本来也可能走上这条不归路
It could've been my son, Michael.
但他很幸运
But it wasn't.
我想我应该感谢上帝
And I suppose I have God to thank for that.
上帝 还有劳伦斯•泰勒
God and Lawrence Taylor.
第一秒
One Mississippi.
（麦克在密大时入选全国最佳阵容）
（并且在苏小姐的帮助下 获得了优秀学生称号）
（柯林斯跟随妈妈的足迹）
（加入了密西西比大学的啦啦队）
（肖恩和莉•安妮仍住在孟菲斯）
（小肖得到了教练所承诺的所有东西）
新英格兰爱国者队与巴尔地摩乌鸦队...
The New England Patriots have traded...
交换了第23顺位的选秀权
the 23rd pick to the Baltimore Ravens.
巴尔地摩乌鸦队选择了2009年NFL选秀第23顺位
And with the 23rd pick in the 2009 NFL draft...
来自密西西比大学的进攻前锋 麦克•欧尔
the Baltimore Ravens select Michael Oher, offensive tackle, Mississippi.